Fm Movie
Fm Movie
NEW YORK (UNITED STATES)
NEW YORK (AS)
Thank you all for coming to the event, especially the Marquises of...
Terima kasih telah hadir di acara ini, terutama para Marquise...
BANGKOK (THAILAND)
BANGKOK (THAILAND)
Inés.
Inés.
Please say yes.
Tolong bilang ya.
Since I met you, I've been the happiest woman in the world.
Sejak bertemu denganmu, aku sangat bahagia.
PANAMA CITY (PANAMA)
KOTA PANAMA
Hey, I have some really good news for you. The ambassador has given the go-ahead.
Aku punya kabar baik untukmu. Duta besar sudah memberi izin.
SPANISH EMBASSY
KEDUTAAN SPANYOL
Yes. I've sent you a link so you can see which room you prefer, okay?
Ya. Aku sudah kirim tautan agar kau bisa lihat kamar mana yang kau suka.
With the dimensions and so on. Oh, hey,
Dengan ukuran dan sebagainya.
the day after tomorrow, they'll call you from the Ministry.
Lusa, Kementerian akan meneleponmu.
They're going to pick up all the material, okay?
Mereka akan ambil semua bahannya.
TOKYO (JAPAN)
TOKYO (JEPANG)
SPANISH EMBASSY
KEDUTAAN BESAR SPANYOL
Good work, Takeshi.
Kerja bagus, Takeshi.
Thank you for your work.
Terima kasih.
AGENT ZETA
AGEN ZETA
RIBEIRA SACRA, GALICIA (SPAIN)
RIBEIRA SACRA, GALICIA (SPANYOL)
NATIONAL INTELLIGENCE CENTER (CNI) MADRID (SPAIN)
PUSAT INTELIJEN NASIONAL (CNI) MADRID (SPANYOL)
Here it is.
Ini dia.
Operation Ciénaga, hot off the presses.
Operasi Ciénaga, baru saja dirilis.
What do we know about it?
Ada informasi apa?
Well, that the four murdered agents participated in it
Empat agen yang dibunuh terlibat dalam kasus itu
and, since then, all of them had false identities.
dan sejak itu, semuanya punya identitas palsu.
Elena, if the press connects the dots, all hell will break loose.
Elena, jika pers tahu kaitannya, situasi akan kacau.
You know what you have to do. Terrorism, ISIS, Al Qaeda, you name it.
Kau tahu yang harus dilakukan. Terorisme, ISIS, Al-Qaeda, apa saja.
Okay.
Baiklah.
In the dossier, there was one more file.
Ada satu fail lagi di berkas itu.
This one.
Yang ini.
Get me the minister.
Hubungi Pak Menteri.
None of this gets out of here until we know what we're dealing with.
Semua ini tak boleh tersebar sampai kita tahu yang dihadapi.
All right.
Baiklah.
What are you going to do?
Kau akan lakukan apa?
The only thing I can do.
Hal yang bisa kulakukan.
Pepe! I have to go.
Pepe! Aku harus pergi.
All right. I'll finish.
Baik. Aku akan selesaikan.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
How subtle.
Terang-terangan.
With a phone call, you wouldn't have agreed.
Jika kutelepon, kau tak akan setuju.
I'm not agreeing to anything.
Aku tak menyetujui apa pun.
You haven't turned on the TV today, have you?
Kau belum menonton TV hari ini, ya?
I don't have a TV.
Aku tak punya TV.
That's why I'm here, to disconnect.
Aku di sini untuk menyepi.
- I'm on leave, in case you don't remember. - I remember.
- Aku sedang cuti, jika kau lupa. - Aku ingat.
I asked you for a year. Half a year ago.
Aku cuti setahun. Ini baru enam bulan.
We'll talk six months from now.
Kita bicara enam bulan lagi.
I'll be right back.
Aku akan kembali.
Iago.
Iago.
Go on, take this. Like this.
Ayo, ambil ini. Seperti ini.
You have to take the spoon.
Kau harus ambil sendoknya.
There.
Itu dia.
Come on, you can do it. Come on.
Ayo, kau bisa.
Way to go, Mom. You're a champ.
Bagus, Bu. Kau hebat.
Why didn't you tell me?
Mengapa tak beri tahu aku?
That's it. She has good and bad days.
Bagus. Kondisinya tak stabil.
But when I came back from Beirut, she'd stopped speaking.
Dia berhenti bicara saat aku kembali dari Beirut.
Very good.
Bagus sekali.
That's it.
Itu dia.
You have your mother's eyes.
Matamu mirip ibumu.
She says my personality is just like his.
Dia bilang kepribadianku mirip ayahku.
Right, Mom?
Benar, Bu?
Your father is a legend, they say.
Kata orang, ayahmu legenda.
All the fallen end up as legends. Come on.
Semua yang gugur menjadi legenda. Ayo.
The last one. That's it.
Yang terakhir. Itu dia.
Andreia.
Andreia.
Very good.
Bagus sekali.
Here, you take it.
Ini, ambillah.
The four victims lived under false identities,
Keempat korban punya identitas palsu,
scattered in Spanish embassies.
tersebar di kedutaan Spanyol.
- All were protected by the government. - They were hiding from someone. Why?
- Semua dilindungi pemerintah. - Mereka bersembunyi. Mengapa?
No idea. But that someone has found them and executed them.
Entah. Namun, seseorang telah menemukan dan mengeksekusi mereka.
Why those four?
Mengapa mereka?
The victims had a connection.
Para korban punya kaitan.
They participated in a mission 37 years ago.
Mereka ikut dalam misi 37 tahun lalu.
They are former members of CESID, old-school spies.
Mereka mantan anggota CESID, mata-mata lama.
What kind of mission?
Misi seperti apa?
I can't tell you anything else. There are no records of the mission.
Aku tak bisa beri tahu. Tak ada catatan misinya.
We leave little in writing, but we leave something.
Hanya sedikit dokumen, tapi ada sesuatu.
Right. But nothing was written about Operation Ciénaga,
Benar, tapi tak ada dokumen tentang Operasi Ciénaga
or it was destroyed. I don't know.
atau sudah dihancurkan. Aku tak tahu.
Look, Elena, my priority now is my mother.
Elena, prioritasku sekarang ibuku.
Whatever time she has left, I'd like to be by her side.
Aku mau menemaninya di sisa hidupnya.
- I can totally understand. - Okay.
- Aku bisa mengerti. - Baik.
But there could be another murder, Iago.
Mungkin akan ada pembunuhan lain.
Five agents were involved in Operation Ciénaga.
Lima agen terlibat dalam Operasi Ciénaga.
Only four victims have been found.
Hanya empat korban ditemukan.
- You can't locate the fifth. - Exactly.
- Kau tak temukan yang kelima. - Tepat.
His current name is Salvador Ancares.
Namanya saat ini Salvador Ancares.
He has disappeared, he didn't go to work today.
Dia menghilang, tak bekerja hari ini.
He was relocated to the embassy in Tallinn, Estonia.
Dia pindah ke kedutaan di Tallinn, Estonia.
He's either dead or has gone into hiding.
Entah dia sudah mati atau bersembunyi.
Surely. But finding him is much more important than you think.
Tentu. Namun, kita harus menemukannya.
Ancares is the only person who can tell us what Operation Ciénaga was
Hanya Ancares yang bisa memberi tahu soal Operasi Ciénaga
and who is killing our people.
dan siapa yang membunuh mereka.
I'm sorry, Elena, but this is what you get.
Maaf, Elena, tapi keputusanku sudah bulat.
I'll talk to you in six months. I already told you.
Sudah kubilang, aku akan kembali enam bulan lagi.
If she could speak, your mother would advise you to agree to this.
Jika bisa bicara, ibumu akan menyarankanmu melakukannya.
Excuse me?
Apa?
I swear I didn't want you to find out like this.
Aku tak ingin kau tahu seperti ini.
What the hell is this, a joke?
Apa ini, lelucon?
It's the file of Salvador Ancares.
Itu berkas Salvador Ancares.
Ciénaga, 1987.
Ciénaga, 1987.
He's the fifth agent I want you to locate and protect.
Dia agen kelima yang aku ingin kau lindungi.
No, my father... He died on a mission when I was a baby.
Tidak, ayahku... Dia tewas dalam misi saat aku bayi.
It can't be him.
Ini tak mungkin dia.
Right.
Benar.
Éric Baena died 34 years ago.
Éric Baena meninggal 34 tahun lalu.
He and the four agents were buried
Dia dan empat agen dimakamkan
before being relocated under these new identities.
sebelum diberikan identitas baru.
My mother wouldn't lie to me about this.
Ibuku tak akan membohongiku.
- I'm sorry. - It can't be him.
- Maaf. - Tak mungkin.
I'm also only just finding out now.
Aku juga baru tahu sekarang.
Iago, find Ancares.
Iago, temukan Ancares.
Let him tell you what the hell is going on.
Dia akan beri tahu yang terjadi.
My father is dead.
Ayahku sudah tewas.
Iago, your mother is in bed now. I'm leaving.
Iago, ibumu sudah tidur. Aku pamit.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
- See you tomorrow.
- Sampai besok.
My father, is he still alive?
Apakah ayahku masih hidup?
Say something, Mom.
Katakan sesuatu, Bu.
Come on. A gesture, anything.
Ayolah. Sebuah isyarat, apa saja.
SPANISH EMBASSY
KEDUTAAN BESAR SPANYOL
He was retiring today, that's why it's like this.
Dia pensiun hari ini, makanya begini.
We were waiting for him.
Kami menunggunya.
- When he didn't show up-- - His desk?
- Saat dia tak muncul... - Mejanya?
This one.
Yang ini.
- Has he received any letters or packages? - No.
- Apa dia menerima surat atau paket? - Tidak.
Something he bought that could've been shipped to him?
Sesuatu yang dia beli dan dikirim kepadanya?
No, he didn't usually receive anything here.
Tidak, dia tak menerima apa pun di sini.
- Are you sure? - Oh, yes.
- Kau yakin? - Ya.
- His cigarettes. - This right here?
- Rokoknya. - Yang ini?
Yes.
Ya.
He smoked, but his wife didn't know, so he had them sent here.
Dia merokok, tapi istrinya tak tahu, jadi dikirim ke sini.
A carton a week, every Friday.
Satu pak seminggu, setiap Jumat.
Today is Thursday.
Hari ini Kamis.
May I have a second alone, please?
Boleh tinggalkan aku sebentar?
- Sure. - Thanks.
- Tentu. - Terima kasih.
Why hasn't he turned up like the others? He must be alive.
Mengapa tak muncul seperti yang lain? Dia pasti masih hidup.
I'll get the camera footage from the area.
Akan kuminta rekaman kamera.
Ancares or his assassin must have left some trace.
Ancares atau pembunuhnya pasti meninggalkan jejak.
Talk to his wife. See what you get out of her.
Bicara pada istrinya. Lihat yang bisa kau dapat.
I'll call you when I get the footage.
Kutelepon saat dapat rekamannya.
Elena, just one thing.
Elena, satu hal lagi.
He has another son.
Dia punya putra lagi.
Did you know that?
Kau tahu itu?
Zeta, the important thing now is to find Ancares, okay?
Zeta, yang penting sekarang menemukan Ancares, paham?
Right.
Baiklah.
Is your mom here?
Ibumu ada di rumah?
- Hi. Jesús, right? - Yes.
- Hai. Jesús, bukan? - Ya.
- Come on in. - Thank you.
- Masuk. - Terima kasih.
Have you noticed any strange behavior lately?
Ada perilaku aneh belakangan ini?
On some days, he did act... strange.
Terkadang, dia memang bersikap aneh.
Once he did say that he thought someone was following him, but...
Dia pernah bilang ada yang mengikutinya,
who would follow a cultural attaché in Estonia?
tapi siapa yang akan mengikuti atase budaya di Estonia?
We don't know.
Kami tak tahu.
Does it have anything to do with this?
Apa ada kaitannya dengan ini?
Listen to me, don't worry, we'll find him. Do you hear me?
Tenang, kita akan temukan dia. Kau dengar?
Mrs. Karlsson, is there somewhere in the house where he spends more time?
Ny. Karlsson, ada ruangan tempat dia sering habiskan waktu?
Mrs. Karlsson. Calm down.
Ny. Karlsson. Tenanglah.
In here.
Di dalam sini.
CLICK ON THE BUTTON TO START DECRYPTION
TEKAN TOMBOL UNTUK MULAI DEKRIPSI
Good morning, good afternoon, good evening.
Selamat pagi, sore, malam.
If you're watching this, the five of us from Ciénaga have been hunted down.
Jika kau menonton ini, kami berlima dari Ciénaga telah diburu.
If you came to kill me, you won't find me.
Jika mau membunuhku, kau tak akan menemukanku.
Nor will I tell you anything about that mission or what happened. Nothing.
Aku juga tak akan cerita tentang misi itu atau apa yang terjadi.
Please don't hurt them. They have nothing to do with it, they know nothing.
Jangan sakiti mereka. Mereka tak terkait dan tak tahu apa-apa.
And if you're one of the good guys...
Jika kau salah satu orang baik...
Good guys, bad guys, it's complicated to draw the line in what we do, I know.
Orang baik, jahat, sulit membedakannya dalam pekerjaan kita, aku tahu.
Two things. Protect my family,
Dua hal. Lindungi keluargaku
and in that envelope you have everything you need for now.
dan dalam amplop itu ada yang kau butuhkan untuk saat ini.
Iago. We're checking the codes, which look like ours.
Iago. Kami memeriksa kodenya, tampaknya mirip kode kita.
- He didn't tell you anything else? - Nothing more.
- Dia tak beri tahu hal lain? - Tidak.
- Chief, come take a look at this. - Let's see, just a moment.
- Bu kepala, lihat ini. - Mari lihat, tunggu sebentar.
The codes lead us to GPS coordinates here.
Kodenya membawa kita ke koordinat GPS di sini.
Zeta, confirmed. The codes are ours.
Zeta, dikonfirmasi. Itu kode kita.
Son of a bitch.
Berengsek.
Zeta?
Zeta?
Turn around, God damn it!
Balik badan, Keparat!
Colombian Intelligence Service.
Badan Intelijen Kolombia.
Drop your weapon.
Turunkan senjatamu.
Salomé Suárez. Right.
Salomé Suárez. Benar.
Your code name?
Nama kodemu?
Alpha.
Alfa.
- And yours, Jesús Bao? - Zeta.
- Kodemu, Jesús Bao? - Zeta.
I earned the name "Alpha" because I was top of my class.
Aku dapat nama "Alfa" karena aku yang terbaik.
I guess you were the worst in yours.
Kurasa kau yang terburuk.
Why is Colombia looking for a former Spanish spy relocated to Estonia?
Mengapa Kolombia mencari mantan mata-mata Spanyol di Estonia?
In the last few days, someone has been following Ancares.
Beberapa hari terakhir, Ancares diikuti.
I don't know. When I arrived, he had already disappeared.
Entahlah. Saat aku tiba, dia sudah menghilang.
And instead of identifying yourself, you attack me and steal from me.
Alih-alih memperkenalkan diri, kau menyerangku dan mencuri dariku.
I'm sorry?
Apa?
I'm the one who ended up across a windshield, aren't I?
Aku yang berakhir di kaca depan mobil, bukan?
- Does the envelope say where Ancares is? - How do you know there's an envelope?
- Amplopnya beri tahu lokasi Ancares? - Bagaimana tahu ada amplop?
I told you, I was top of my class.
Sudah kubilang, aku yang terbaik.
Why didn't the CNI have Ancares under control?
Mengapa CNI tak mengendalikan Ancares?
- You don't want anything? - I don't drink.
- Tak mau apa pun? - Aku tak minum.
- I'll treat you.
- Akan kutraktir.
- Have you been doing this for a long time? - Too long.
- Kau sudah lama melakukan ini? - Terlalu lama.
- Why did you choose this profession? - Someone has to do it, right?
- Mengapa memilih profesi ini? - Harus ada yang melakukannya, bukan?
Yeah. And you're the type who never tells his real name.
Ya. Kau tipe orang yang tak pernah beri tahu nama asli.
I can't tell you because I can't remember it.
Aku tak memberi tahu karena tak ingat.
Do you go around telling people yours?
Kau beri tahu orang-orang namamu?
It depends. Among colleagues.
Tergantung. Di antara rekan kerja.
No, we're not colleagues.
Kita bukan rekan kerja.
So, what do you want to do?
Apa yang mau kau lakukan?
You do as you please. I'm waiting for orders.
Lakukan sesukamu. Aku tunggu perintah.
Let's try again.
Mari coba lagi.
- Operation Ciénaga took place in Colombia? - Operation Ciénaga?
- Operasi Ciénaga dilakukan di Kolombia? - Operasi Ciénaga?
If you're looking for Ancares, it must have happened on Colombian soil.
Jika kau mencari Ancares, pasti terjadi di Kolombia.
- Don't play dumb. - I'm not playing dumb.
- Jangan pura-pura bodoh. - Tidak.
- You've been doing it from start. - I wouldn't know where to start.
- Kau melakukannya sejak awal. - Entah mulai dari mana.
- You wouldn't? - No.
- Tak tahu? - Tidak.
I'll tell you what.
Begini saja.
If you tell me where Ancares is,
Jika kau beri tahu di mana Ancares,
I'll tell you what I know about Operation Ciénaga.
akan kuberi tahu tentang Operasi Ciénaga.
It's a win-win, see? We're both looking for the same thing.
Sama-sama menguntungkan. Kita mencari hal yang sama.
I don't work as a team.
Aku bekerja sendiri.
From now on, you do.
Mulai sekarang, kita tim.
Whatever you say.
Terserah kau.
Talk to me.
Bicaralah.
I spoke with my Colombian counterpart.
Aku hubungi rekanku di Kolombia.
Alpha is her best agent. Top of her class.
Alfa agen terbaiknya. Terbaik di kelasnya.
Ancares and the four dead agents operated illegally in Colombia.
Ancares dan empat agen itu beroperasi ilegal di Kolombia.
It seems that Operation Ciénaga was a black op for all agencies.
Tampaknya Operasi Ciénaga adalah operasi rahasia bagi semua agensi.
So, now, Colombia and Spain have the same objective,
Kini, Kolombia dan Spanyol punya satu tujuan,
to find Ancares and clarify what the hell happened 37 years ago.
menemukan Ancares dan menjelaskan apa yang terjadi 37 tahun lalu.
What have they promised you?
Mereka janjikan apa?
Colombia knows more about the operation than we do.
Kolombia tahu lebih banyak tentang operasinya.
But they won't give us anything until they talk to him.
Mereka tak akan beri apa pun sampai bicara dengannya.
If we bring him to them, they'll give us the murderer.
Jika kita berikan dia, mereka akan beri pembunuhnya.
They seem to know who it is.
Mereka tahu pelakunya.
Something seems fishy to me.
Ada yang mencurigakan.
Zeta, from now on, the DNI and us are working as a team.
Zeta, mulai sekarang, DNI dan kita bekerja sebagai tim.
- You've gotta be fucking kidding me. - My hands are tied.
- Kau pasti bercanda. - Aku tak bisa apa-apa.
The coordinates. Have you found out anything?
Koordinatnya. Kau menemukan sesuatu?
Yes, they lead us to St. John the Baptist Cemetery, Rio de Janeiro.
Ya, itu koordinat Pemakaman Santo Yohanes Pembaptis, Rio de Janeiro.
We checked all the Center's files for services linked to this place.
Kami memeriksa semua berkas layanan Pusat yang terkait tempat ini.
We found an invoice from 1990 with funeral expenses.
Kami menemukan faktur biaya pemakaman dari tahun 1990.
It's a tombstone with a name and surname.
Batu nisan dengan nama dan nama keluarga.
Say no more.
Aku paham.
- Ancares buried Éric Baena there. - That's right.
- Ancares mengubur Éric Baena di sana. - Benar.
Zeta, you're going to Brazil.
Zeta, pergilah ke Brasil.
ST. JOHN THE BAPTIST CEMETERY
PEMAKAMAN SANTO YOHANES PEMBAPTIS
Can you hear me?
Kau mendengarku?
Loud and clear.
Sangat jelas.
Sweeper. Orange suit.
Penyapu. Baju oranye.
Alpha, I've found the tomb.
Alfa, aku menemukan makamnya.
Now what?
Sekarang apa?
Someone has laid fresh flowers.
Ada yang menaruh bunga segar.
Hey. You. Stop right there.
Hei. Kau. Berhenti di sana.
I'm telling you to stop.
Aku menyuruhmu berhenti.
- Hey, can I ask you a question? - Sorry, ma'am, I'm working.
- Boleh bertanya? - Maaf, Bu, aku sedang bekerja.
Hey! Stop right there.
Hei! Berhenti.
Hey! You son of a bitch!
Hei! Dasar bajingan!
Stop!
Berhenti!
Shit!
Sial!
Stop! Hey!
Berhenti! Hei!
Okay, freeze! Freeze.
Baik, jangan bergerak!
Hands, let me see them.
Keluarkan tanganmu.
Turn around. Turn around.
Balik badan.
The gun you've got there, put it down slowly, okay? Slowly.
Letakkan senjatamu pelan-pelan, paham? Pelan-pelan.
Keep walking.
Terus berjalan.
Easy. That's it.
Pelan-pelan. Bagus.
Ancares. Where is Ancares?
Ancares. Di mana Ancares?
You find that funny? Huh?
Menurut kalian itu lucu?
Drop your weapons!
Letakkan senjatamu!
Drop your weapons, motherfuckers!
Letakkan senjata kalian!
You'd better drop your weapons.
Sebaiknya letakkan senjata kalian.
Go on, God damn it!
Lakukan, Berengsek!
Okay. Play along with them. Okay, okay, okay.
Baiklah. Turuti mereka.
The bag.
Tasnya.
Give him your bag.
Berikan tasmu.
The bag!
Tasnya!
All good?
Semua beres?
You know the drill.
Kalian tahu harus apa.
You guys, you can leave.
Kalian bisa pergi.
- Quickly. - Come on, God damn it!
- Cepat. - Ayo, Berengsek!
Come on, let's go.
Ayo, mari pergi.
The old man doesn't want the girl.
Pria tua itu tak mau gadis itu.
Hey!
Hei!
God! Fucking hell!
Astaga! Berengsek!
Good, good. We're almost there.
Bagus. Kita hampir sampai.
We're here.
Kita sampai.
That's it. Come on, let's go.
Itu dia. Ayo, jalan.
Slowly. Get in.
Pelan-pelan. Masuk.
Come on, let's go.
Ayo, jalan.
Everything all right at the embassy?
Semua baik-baik saja di kedutaan?
Of course it is. Nothing ever happens at that embassy.
Tentu saja. Tak ada yang terjadi di kedutaan itu.
Did you need to put on this circus?
Kau perlu melakukan sirkus ini?
You're supposed to be a professional.
Kau seharusnya profesional.
That's not the attitude.
Bukan bersikap begitu.
I'm going to ask you again, why are you looking for me?
Aku akan bertanya lagi, mengapa kau mencariku?
To protect you.
Untuk melindungimu.
Jesús Bao.
Jesús Bao.
You're not able to protect yourself. What's your nom de guerre?
Kau bahkan tak bisa melindungi diri. Apa nama samaranmu?
Zeta.
Zeta.
Is everyone okay at the House on Cuesta de las Perdices?
Semua baik-baik saja di Markas di Cuesta de las Perdices?
We call it "the Center" now.
Namanya "Pusat" sekarang.
Lots of Colombian women at the Center?
Banyak wanita Kolombia di Pusat?
Joint mission, until your goons threw her out of a moving van.
Misi gabungan, sampai anak buahmu melemparnya keluar dari van.
- Why is Colombia looking for me? - You know why.
- Mengapa Kolombia mencariku? - Kau tahu alasannya.
To clarify what happened 37 years ago on Colombian soil.
Untuk jelaskan kejadian 37 tahun lalu di Kolombia.
Operation Ciénaga. What happened?
Operasi Ciénaga. Ada apa?
I'll ask the questions for now. Okay, Zeta?
Aku yang akan bertanya untuk saat ini. Paham, Zeta?
You've been to my house and you've seen my family. How are they?
Kau sudah ke rumahku dan bertemu keluargaku. Apa kabar mereka?
Why don't you enlighten me with your wisdom and tell me what you see?
Mengapa tak jelaskan kepadaku dan katakan yang kau lihat?
Do you have any other family that needs protection?
Kau punya keluarga lain yang butuh perlindungan?
Very good, Zeta. The kid did his homework.
Bagus sekali, Zeta. Anak ini sudah lakukan riset.
In Spain, it's on record that you were married and had a child.
Di Spanyol, kau tercatat sudah menikah dan punya anak.
That life belonged to Éric Baena.
Hidup itu milik Éric Baena.
You know where Éric Baena has been buried for 34 years.
Kau tahu di mana Éric Baena dikubur selama 34 tahun.
Be very careful with this life, Zeta, very careful. It's complicated.
Hati-hati dengan kehidupan ini, Zeta, sangat hati-hati. Ini rumit.
The Center will allow you to live many lives, many lives.
Pusat akan mengizinkanmu menjalani banyak kehidupan.
All those lives, Zeta, you'll live them in exchange for your own.
Semua kehidupan itu, Zeta, kau akan jalani sebagai ganti nyawamu.
Mine is there now, in Estonia, in Tallinn.
Kehidupanku sekarang ada di Estonia, di Tallinn.
- Will you protect my family, yes or no? - I've already told you, that's my job.
- Kau akan lindungi keluargaku? - Sudah kubilang, itu tugasku.
But you'll have to tell us about Operation Ciénaga
Kau harus jelaskan Operasi Ciénaga
and why it could hurt us.
dan mengapa berbahaya.
How do you intend to save my life by taking shots in the dark?
Bagaimana kau ingin menyelamatkanku tanpa tahu apa-apa?
There are no records of the mission. We assume that CESID shredded everything.
Tak ada catatan misi. Kami menduga CESID menghancurkan semuanya.
There was nothing to shred. It was the '80s.
Tak ada catatannya. Itu tahun 1980-an.
Who wants you dead and why?
Siapa yang mau kalian mati?
Calm down. Always stay calm.
Tenanglah. Selalu tenang.
The whole mission was set up around a Colombian estate
Seluruh misi diatur di sekitar wilayah Kolombia
very close to Medellín. La Ciénaga.
yang dekat dengan Medellín. La Ciénaga.
Why did the Center act on its own in foreign territory?
Mengapa Pusat bertindak di wilayah asing?
Because we came to La Ciénaga following a cocaine star,
Karena kami datang ke La Ciénaga mengikuti bandar besar kokaina,
a guy who was sharp as hell. Sito Baltar.
pria yang sangat pintar. Sito Baltar.
Sito Baltar?
Sito Baltar?
The CNI doesn't deal with drug trafficking.
CNI tak tangani perdagangan narkoba.
Sito was the bait to get to Tirapu.
Sito adalah umpan menangkap Tirapu.
The ETA member.
Anggota ETA.
Asier Zabaltegui, alias "Tirapu."
Asier Zabaltegui, alias "Tirapu".
The biggest son of a bitch in ETA's all-powerful military wing.
Bajingan terbesar di sayap militer ETA yang sangat berkuasa.
How Tirapu ended up in Colombia
Bagaimana Tirapu berakhir di Kolombia
is the beginning of our tragedy, yours and mine.
adalah awal dari tragedi kita, kau dan aku.
In the '80s, Tirapu had a meteoric rise through ETA's young recruits.
Pada tahun 1980-an, Tirapu maju pesat melalui rekrutan muda ETA.
He wasn't even 25 and he was already leading the Biscay Command.
Usianya belum genap 25 tahun dan dia sudah memimpin Komando Biscay.
And the kid had what it took.
Anak itu punya kemampuan.
If he could sense Spanish in you, you were dead.
Kau dibunuh jika ketahuan keturunan Spanyol.
Instinctively, without even realizing it,
Secara naluriah, tanpa disadari,
Tirapu had become a rising star in the world of terrorism,
Tirapu telah menjadi bintang yang naik daun di dunia terorisme,
a perfect killing machine.
mesin pembunuh yang sempurna.
Until he went too far.
Sampai dia kelewatan.
Hit it, hit it!
Ledakkan!
Damn it! Shit!
Berengsek! Sial!
There it is!
Itu dia!
Fuck, he's still alive.
Sial, dia masih hidup.
Get rid of that dog!
Bunuh dia!
After that massacre, the government decided to eliminate him.
Usai pembantaian, pemerintah ingin menyingkirkannya.
They gave us carte blanche, an eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth.
Mereka memberi kami wewenang penuh untuk menghukumnya.
That way, the government could score some political points.
Pemerintah bisa dapat dukungan politik.
The problem was that ETA saw the move coming
Masalahnya, ETA mengetahui langkah itu
and exiled its star terrorist to Colombia.
dan mengasingkan bintang terorisnya ke Kolombia.
How did you locate Tirapu?
Bagaimana kau cari Tirapu?
National Police intelligence informed us that the narco, Sito Baltar,
Intelijen Kepolisian Nasional beri tahu bahwa bandar narkoba, Sito Baltar,
met regularly with Tirapu, and we obviously followed that lead.
sering bertemu dengan Tirapu dan kami tentu mengikuti petunjuk itu.
Slowly.
Pelan-pelan.
Slowly, okay? This isn't sand, this costs money.
Pelan-pelan. Ini bukan pasir, ini mahal.
Sito Baltar. What a character.
Sito Baltar. Karakter yang hebat.
Paco! You hear me? Paco!
Paco! Kau dengar aku?
In the '80s, Sito Baltar was the undisputed king of moving cocaine,
Tahun 1980-an, Sito Baltar adalah raja tak terkalahkan dalam perdagangan kokaina,
and like any good king, he had total control over certain ports in Colombia
dan seperti raja lainnya, dia memiliki kendali penuh pelabuhan di Kolombia,
from which shipments sailed out to the world.
tempat pengiriman kokaina ke seluruh dunia.
Sito paid well and kept everyone happy.
Sito membayar dengan baik dan membuat semua orang senang.
If you got in his way, he'd make it clear who ruled both sides of the Atlantic.
Jika menghalanginya, dia akan menegaskan siapa penguasa kedua sisi Atlantik.
Because Sito Baltar knew he was well protected by his friends in the FARC.
Karena Sito Baltar tahu dia dilindungi oleh teman-temannya di FARC.
Man. You look good in green, dude.
Astaga. Kau terlihat bagus dengan warna hijau, Bung.
- How's the family? Good? - Good, all good.
- Bagaimana keluargamu? Baik? - Baik.
By protecting him, the guerrilla was feeding its own business,
Dengan melindunginya, gerilyawan lancar berbisnis,
and it wasn't the revolution.
dan itu bukan revolusi.
It was cocaine and weapons.
Namun, kokaina dan senjata.
Like my mom used to say, the little fish that bites its own tail.
Seperti kata ibuku, itu adalah lingkaran setan.
The deal was simple.
Kesepakatannya sederhana.
ETA trained the FARC in making and handling explosives,
ETA melatih FARC untuk membuat dan menangani bahan peledak
and the FARC supplied weapons to ETA.
dan FARC memasok senjata untuk ETA.
And Baltar, for a nice cut, brought those weapons into Euskadi.
Baltar, dengan harga yang murah, membawa senjata itu ke Negara Bask.
We take the tip, heat it and, at the same time...
Kita ambil ujungnya, panaskan, kemudian...
Hey!
Hei!
So we've got a narco with his ports and his ships,
Ada bandar narkoba dengan pelabuhan dan kapal,
a guerrilla army with its soldiers and weapons,
pasukan gerilya dengan prajurit dan senjata,
and a well-camouflaged ETA member sending loads of weapons back home.
dan anggota ETA yang menyamar mengirim banyak senjata ke rumah.
- What are we missing here? - The weapons. Where did they come from?
- Apa yang kita lewatkan? - Senjatanya. Dari mana asalnya?
From La Ciénaga,
Dari La Ciénaga,
the ranch of the most impressive arms dealer in the Americas.
peternakan penjual senjata paling mengesankan di Amerika.
Who?
Siapa?
I'll give you another history lesson.
Kuberi pelajaran sejarah lagi.
In 1985, that is, 40 years ago, I was in charge of...
Pada tahun 1985, 40 tahun yang lalu, aku memimpin...
Let's call it "illegal port traffic."
Sebut saja "lalu lintas pelabuhan ilegal".
And sometimes, mainly by luck,
Terkadang, karena keberuntungan,
we were ahead of the curve and we were able to prevent
kami lebih unggul dan berhasil mencegah
a small portion of the weapons from entering Spain.
sebagian kecil senjata memasuki Spanyol.
What the hell are you doing, asshole? Keep still.
Apa yang kau lakukan, Berengsek? Jangan bergerak.
Give me that.
Berikan itu.
It was in one of those operations that we discovered
Dalam salah satu operasi itu kami menemukan
the name of the person supplying the weapons
nama orang yang memasok senjata
that ended up in ETA's all-powerful military wing.
yang ada di sayap militer ETA yang sangat berkuasa.
Furiase. Teo Furiase.
Furiase. Teo Furiase.
Teo Furiase, aka "the Fury of God."
Teo Furiase, alias "Amarah Tuhan".
Furiase had built his entire life in La Ciénaga.
Furiase membangun hidupnya di La Ciénaga.
It was his home, his temple, his bunker.
Itu rumahnya, kuilnya, bunkernya.
And we found out Furiase was completely untouchable.
Ternyata Furiase benar-benar tak tersentuh.
He had built his empire by bribing judges, businessmen, and politicians,
Dia membangun kerajaannya dengan menyuap hakim, pengusaha, dan politisi,
who let him operate freely across Latin America.
yang mengizinkannya beroperasi bebas di seluruh Amerika Latin.
We never would've gone after him if he hadn't made contact with Tirapu.
Kami tak akan mengejarnya jika dia tak berhubungan dengan Tirapu.
But he did. And that's how five of us from the Agency ended up in Colombia.
Namun, dia berhubungan. Lalu kami berlima dari Agensi datang ke Kolombia.
Hey.
Hei.
- Just a second. - My turn.
- Tunggu. - Giliranku.
No, nothing.
Tak ada apa-apa.
Tirapu was a pro. He never so much as stuck a toe out of La Ciénaga's door.
Tirapu profesional. Dia tak pernah terlihat di La Ciénaga.
Time and money were running out, and we had nothing.
Waktu dan uang menipis dan kami tak dapat apa-apa.
Our higher-ups started losing patience.
Para petinggi mulai kehilangan kesabaran.
How did you manage to find him?
Bagaimana kau menemukannya?
A tip-off.
Sebuah petunjuk.
- A tip-off? - A tip-off. It's always a tip-off.
- Sebuah petunjuk? - Selalu sebuah petunjuk.
Was your source trustworthy?
Sumbermu bisa dipercaya?
I would have trusted him with my life.
Aku memercayainya dengan nyawaku.
He provided us with the day, time and place
Dia memberi kami hari, waktu, dan tempat
of an exchange of briefcases between the Fury of God, Baltar and Tirapu.
pertukaran koper antara Amarah Tuhan, Baltar, dan Tirapu.
The Holy Trinity of sons of bitches together in the same place.
Tritunggal Mahakudus para bajingan berkumpul di tempat yang sama.
- Have you seen all this I put on for you? - How wonderful.
- Kau lihat semua yang kusiapkan untukmu? - Luar biasa.
The site was very tricky. Families, children...
Lokasinya rumit. Keluarga, anak-anak...
But it was our only chance.
Namun, itu satu-satunya kesempatan kami.
Tirapu was leaving Colombia that night, and the five of us on Operation Ciénaga
Tirapu akan meninggalkan Kolombia dan kami berlima di Operasi Ciénaga
were convinced that the mission would be quick and clean.
yakin bahwa misinya akan cepat dan bersih.
I guess if someone is taking revenge on the CNI 37 years later,
Jika ada yang balas dendam pada CNI 37 tahun kemudian,
it's because the operation was not as clean as you had imagined.
itu karena operasinya tak sebersih dugaanmu.
- What went wrong? - Keep one thing in mind.
- Apa yang salah? - Ingat satu hal.
Tirapu was a colossal son of a bitch, but he was no fool.
Tirapu bajingan jahat, tapi dia tak bodoh.
Okay, they're here.
Baik, mereka tiba.
Tirapu chose to be seen on the big day of the festival,
Tirapu memilih muncul di hari penting festival,
the day he knew he would have maximum protection,
ketika dia tahu akan mendapatkan perlindungan maksimum,
with all those families as his best shield.
dengan semua keluarga itu sebagai tamengnya.
- Hey! - Hi!
- Hei! - Hai!
How are you?
Apa kabar?
A cover agent's worst nightmare,
Mimpi terburuk agen menyamar,
causing civilian casualties in a foreign country.
menyebabkan korban sipil di negara asing.
Tirapu knew that no one would go after him in such an environment.
Tirapu tahu tak ada yang mengejarnya di lingkungan begitu.
We had no choice. We had to abort.
Kami tak punya pilihan. Kami harus batalkan misi.
But it wasn't aborted.
Namun, tak dibatalkan.
Hunting down Tirapu had become a state matter.
Memburu Tirapu telah menjadi urusan negara.
He was leaving Colombia and there might not be another chance.
Dia akan meninggalkan Kolombia dan tak ada kesempatan lagi.
And to make matters even worse, that day, someone warned Furiase.
Lebih buruknya, hari itu, seseorang memperingatkan Furiase.
They had discovered that we were on to them.
Mereka tahu kami mengejarnya.
And it all went to shit.
Semuanya jadi kacau.
I was a kid.
Aku masih muda.
That was the most fucked-up moment of my first life as an agent.
Itu momen paling kacau dari kehidupan pertamaku sebagai agen.
Who do you think might be taking revenge on you?
Menurutmu siapa yang akan balas dendam?
Anyone connected to any of the people we took out at that festival.
Siapa pun yang terkait dengan orang yang kami habisi di festival itu.
What do you think?
Bagaimana menurutmu?
Let's do this, okay?
Ayo lakukan ini, ya?
You and I are going to Bogotá.
Kau dan aku akan pergi ke Bogotá.
Right now.
Sekarang juga.
The DNI has questions for you.
DNI punya pertanyaan untukmu.
First, you're going to tell Grandma something, Little Zeta Riding Hood.
Beri tahu Nenek dahulu, Zeta Kecil Berkerudung Merah.
Why the hell do you want to meet the wolf?
Mengapa kau ingin bertemu dengan serigala?
I came to protect you and that's what I plan to do. We're leaving.
Aku datang untuk melindungimu. Kita akan pergi.
Tell them to put down their weapons. I won't tell you twice.
Suruh mereka turunkan senjata. Aku tak akan ulangi.
I'm curious. I want to see how you plan on doing that.
Aku penasaran. Aku ingin tahu rencanamu.
My partner is aiming at you. So don't fool around.
Rekanku membidikmu. Jadi, jangan macam-macam.
- Watch out! - Son of a bitch!
- Hati-hati! - Bajingan!
Drop the fucking weapons! On the ground!
Letakkan senjatanya! Tiarap!
Put the fucking guns on the ground!
Letakkan senjatanya di lantai!
- Easy, easy. - Weapons down.
- Tenang. - Turunkan senjata.
Drop the guns!
Letakkan senjata!
The kid is leaving now!
Anak ini pergi sekarang!
The kid is leaving!
Anak ini akan pergi!
Put the gun down! Drop it!
Letakkan senjata! Jatuhkan!
And get the fucking stuff in the bag. Come on!
Masukkan barangnya ke dalam tas. Ayo!
His things...
Barang-barangnya...
His things in the backpack.
Barangnya di ransel.
All the stuff in the bag.
Masukkan barang ke tas.
Take out the backpack.
Keluarkan ranselnya.
I've listened to you long enough.
Aku sudah lama mendengarmu.
Come on, hurry up. Quickly!
Ayo, cepatlah! Cepat!
- Easy does it. - Forget it. Grab it.
- Pelan-pelan. - Lupakan. Ambillah.
Grab the bag, damn it.
Ambil tasnya, sial.
Go. Come on. Let's go. You, don't move.
Ayo. Mari pergi. Kau, jangan bergerak.
I'll blow your fucking head off.
Akan kuledakkan kepalamu.
That way, damn it!
Sebelah sana, sial!
- Drop the gun! - Stop! Drop it!
- Jatuhkan senjatanya! - Berhenti!
I'll shoot him in the head!
Akan kutembak kepalanya!
Put down your weapons!
Letakkan senjata kalian!
Relax! Put down your weapons.
Tenang! Letakkan senjata kalian.
Put down your weapons.
Letakkan senjata kalian.
Everything's all right!
Semua baik-baik saja!
Everything's fine. Put it down.
Tak apa. Turunkan senjatanya.
The car keys.
Kunci mobilnya!
Give me the keys.
Berikan kuncinya.
The bitch! Go get her, run!
Tangkap dia, lari!
Come on, let's go that way!
Ayo, ke sebelah sana!
Get the fuck out of there! Get out!
Keluar dari sana! Keluar!
Quit doing that, God damn it!
Berhenti melakukan itu, Berengsek!
Come on, damn it.
Ayolah, sial.
You fucking lost.
Kau kalah.
- You lost. - Don't shoot me, please.
- Kau kalah. - Jangan tembak.
- I'm going to kill this bitch. - Don't shoot me.
- Akan kubunuh jalang ini. - Jangan tembak aku.
Easy. Easy!
Pelan-pelan!
- Let him fucking go! - Let him go now, bitch! Fuck!
- Lepaskan dia! - Lepaskan dia, Jalang! Berengsek!
- Relax. - Where's the guy with the motorcycle?
- Tenang. - Di mana pria bermotor itu?
Come on, damn it, get a move on!
Ayo, cepatlah!
Drive, let's go!
Ayo jalan, cepat!
He's crazy! Didn't you see me?
Dia gila! Kau tak melihatku?
- Where are you going? - To the bathroom.
- Kau mau ke mana? - Lavatori.
BOGOTA. THE DNI. IN 5 HOURS WE ACTIVATE
BOGOTÁ. DNI. DALAM LIMA JAM KITA AKTIFKAN
Everything okay?
Semuanya baik?
Everything's wrong, thank God.
Semuanya salah, syukurlah.
COLOMBIAN INTELLIGENCE SERVICE (DNI) BOGOTÁ (COLOMBIA)
BADAN INTELIJEN KOLOMBIA (DNI)
Hello. Alpha.
Halo. Alfa.
- Elena Faron. Pleasure. - Hugo Landa.
- Elena Faron. - Hugo Landa.
Alpha.
Alfa.
Elena Faron, Hugo Landa.
Elena Faron, Hugo Landa.
They're waiting for us inside.
Mereka tunggu kita di dalam.
Ancares, come with me.
Ancares, ikut denganku.
Zeta, you'd better wait at the hotel.
Zeta, kau tunggu di hotel.
- This way. - So my duty's done?
- Lewat sini. - Tugasku usai?
Basically, you're not cleared to enter.
Intinya, kau tak diizinkan masuk.
But your hotel is right across the street. You can walk there.
Hotelmu di seberang jalan. Kau bisa ke sana.
Get some rest. You deserve it. Talk to you later.
Istirahatlah. Kau layak istirahat. Kita bicara nanti.
Excuse me, sir. Please, all your belongings here.
Permisi, Pak. Tolong taruh semua barangmu di sini.
I'm sorry, but I have to keep this.
Maaf, tapi aku harus menyimpan ini.
Good move. Come this way.
Langkah bagus. Lewat sini.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Good morning. Everything is fine here. She slept through the night
PAGI. SEMUA BAIK-BAIK SAJA DI SINI. DIA TIDUR SEMALAMAN.
If you don't mind, I'd prefer the abridged version.
Jika tak keberatan, aku lebih suka versi ringkasnya.
Colombia is after something related to the murders of our agents.
Kolombia mengejar sesuatu terkait dengan pembunuhan agen kita.
We don't know what,
Entah apa,
but they're threatening a diplomatic crisis if we don't cooperate.
tapi mereka ancam krisis diplomatik jika tak bekerja sama.
They insist the only person who can help them is you.
Mereka bersikeras hanya kau yang bisa membantu.
And in exchange, they'll give us the culprit of the embassy murders.
Lalu, mereka memberi kita pelaku pembunuhan kedutaan.
That is a priority for the minister. We need to answer to public opinion.
Itu jadi prioritas menteri. Kita harus tanggapi tekanan publik.
Don't lie, Landa. The minister needs to float in the shit,
Jangan bohong, Landa. Menteri tak perbaiki masalah,
which is what ministers do. They float in the shit.
itu yang dilakukan menteri. Mereka hidup di dalam masalah.
Zeta knows my conditions,
Zeta tahu syaratku,
I collaborate with you one last time and disappear. Alive.
aku bekerja sama untuk terakhir kali dan menghilang. Hidup-hidup.
- Forever. Yeah? - Very well.
- Selamanya. Setuju? - Baiklah.
- Fine. - Now, if you'll excuse me,
- Permisi,
I've got Jordan on the hoop.
aku ingin buang air besar.
- Excuse me? - I need to shit.
- Apa? - Aku mau buang air besar.
Don't you guys shit? Of course, you guys never shit!
Tak pernah buang air besar? Tentu saja, kalian tak pernah!
- We'll wait for you over there. - Jeez.
- Kami tunggu di sana. - Astaga.
Come on.
Ayo.
- Hands. - Hey, relax.
- Angkat tangan. - Hei, tenanglah.
Who are you?
Siapa kalian?
Well, the old Spaniard sent us.
Orang Spanyol tua itu mengirim kami.
Ancares?
Ancares?
- No idea what name he goes by now, but... - Hold it right there.
- Entah siapa namanya kini, tapi... - Berhenti di sana.
Very well.
Baiklah.
I'm Marlon, this is Flaco, and this is Vivi.
Aku Marlon, ini Flaco, dan ini Vivi.
We come unarmed...
Kami tak bawa senjata...
and we just want to help.
dan hanya ingin membantu.
Help with what?
Membantu apa?
The old man will tell you that. For now, you have to trust us.
Pria tua itu akan beri tahu. Kau harus percaya kami.
Flaco.
Flaco.
Easy. Put what you have in your backpack on the table, come on. Go on, both of you.
Perlahan. Taruh isi ransel di meja. Ayo, kalian berdua.
- Deploying equipment. - Very well.
- Keluarkan alatnya. - Baik.
All right, on the table. And no funny business, okay?
Baiklah, di meja. Jangan macam-macam, ya?
Okay.
Baiklah.
- Come on. - Okay, okay.
- Ayo. - Baiklah.
Pass me the earbuds.
Berikan penyuara telinganya.
Good.
Bagus.
Let's get to work.
Ayo bekerja.
Marlon, do you copy?
Marlon, kau dengar?
Darling!
Sayang!
It's good to hear your voice after so long, brother.
Senang mendengar suaramu usai sekian lama.
Hey, we're at the hotel across the street with your new boyfriend.
Kami di hotel seberang jalan dengan pacar barumu.
Zeta, just listen now
Zeta, dengarkan baik-baik
and learn a little from your elders.
dan belajar dari yang lebih tua.
Marlon, something smells rotten in here, but I don't know what it is yet.
Marlon, ada yang tak beres, tapi aku belum tahu apa.
I need you to be my eyes out there, okay?
Aku ingin kau menjadi mataku di luar sana, ya?
Well, don't worry.
Jangan cemas.
That's what I'm here for.
Untuk itulah aku di sini.
And we're all in, working for you.
Kami semua sepakat, bekerja untukmu.
But you have to listen to me and not talk until I tell you.
Namun, kau harus mendengarkanku dan tak bicara sampai kusuruh.
I'm in your hands, Marlon.
Aku ada di tanganmu, Marlon.
And when I'm in your hands, you get very happy.
Saat aku di tanganmu, kau menjadi sangat bahagia.
And that makes me nervous as hell.
Itu membuatku sangat gugup.
Well, that's love, honey.
Itulah cinta, Sayang.
That's what love is.
Itulah cinta.
- Elena Faron. - Welcome!
- Elena Faron. - Hai!
- I've been looking forward to meeting you. - Me too.
- Aku menantikan jumpa kau. - Aku juga.
- Hugo Landa. - How are you?
- Hugo Landa. - Apa kabar?
- Please be seated. - Thank you.
- Silakan duduk. - Terima kasih.
- Good evening, gentlemen. - Good evening.
- Selamat malam, Tuan-Tuan. - Selamat malam.
Well, I'm Diana Herrera. Welcome to Colombia.
Aku Diana Herrera. Selamat datang di Kolombia.
Diana Herrera and Diana the Huntress,
Diana Herrera dan Diana sang Pemburu,
I finally put a face to the person responsible for this festival.
akhirnya aku melihat orang yang bertanggung jawab atas festival ini.
You know a lot about festivals in Colombia, don't you?
Kau tahu banyak soal festival di Kolombia, ya?
Yes, quite a lot. Who are the Three Tenors?
Ya, cukup banyak. Siapa Three Tenors ini?
Mr. Shepherd, Mr. Sheep and Mr. Dog.
Tn. Gembala, Tn, Domba, dan Tn. Anjing.
Diana, what you need here is a good veterinarian.
Diana, kau butuh dokter hewan yang baik.
He's still the same old son of a bitch.
Dia masih bajingan yang sama.
I heard about your good sense of humor.
Aku dengar soal selera humormu.
But don't worry, I'm the one driving.
Jangan cemas, aku yang memimpin.
They're just here to make sure we don't go off the road.
Mereka di sini hanya untuk memastikan kita mengikuti protokol.
That's right. And, as you'll see, we brought you here
Benar. Seperti kau lihat, kami membawamu ke sini
because the DNI wants to clarify what happened on Colombian soil in 1987.
karena DNI ingin tahu yang terjadi di Kolombia pada tahun 1987.
You didn't need to kidnap me for that.
Kalian tak perlu menculikku.
Kidnap you? Sorry, sir, we brought you here to make peace.
Menculikmu? Maaf, Pak, kami bawa kau ke sini untuk berdamai.
Of course. And you're talking to the dove of peace right now.
Tentu saja. Kalian sedang berbicara dengan merpati perdamaian sekarang.
He's yanking their chain.
Dia mempermainkan mereka.
And I think you'd better put that piece away before it goes off.
Kurasa sebaiknya kau simpan senjata itu sebelum meletus.
Well then, are you Salvador Ancares?
Baiklah kalau begitu, apa kau Salvador Ancares?
Yes, for a long time now.
Ya, sudah lama sekali.
- And before that, you were called... - Baena. Éric Baena.
- Sebelum itu, kau dipanggil... - Éric Baena.
- You know it. Let's get to the point. - Of course.
- Kau sudah tahu. Langsung saja. - Tentu saja.
A unit of yours operated illegally on Colombian soil
Unitmu beroperasi secara ilegal di Kolombia
to catch a Spanish terrorist.
untuk menangkap teroris Spanyol.
The mission ended in a massacre. We need to assign responsibility.
Misi berakhir dengan pembantaian. Kami mau yang bertanggung jawab.
Define "responsibility."
Definisikan "tanggung jawab".
The person who gave the order to open fire
Orang yang memberi perintah menembak
in a public place filled with families on a holiday.
di tempat umum yang penuh keluarga saat liburan.
That person is in front of you right now.
Orang itu ada di depanmu sekarang.
The photo, Alonso, please.
Tolong fotonya, Alonso.
Twenty dead and dozens injured.
Dua puluh tewas dan puluhan cedera.
The statute of limitations has expired, Diana.
Batas waktunya sudah berakhir, Diana.
I don't understand what the fuck we're doing here. It's expired.
Aku tak mengerti mengapa kita di sini. Kasus sudah kedaluwarsa.
Do you know what I don't understand? The next one, Alonso, please.
Kau tahu yang tak kupahami? Tolong yang berikutnya, Alonso.
Mr. Ancares, we have obtained some images of you on the day of the embassy bombings.
Tn. Ancares, kami dapat fotomu pada hari pengeboman kedutaan.
They're stinging you, dude.
Mereka memprovokasimu.
Can you see anything unusual about them?
Kau lihat ada hal yang tak biasa?
Be very careful with what you say.
Hati-hati dengan ucapanmu.
No.
Tidak.
No?
Tidak?
No, all normal. I see intelligence agent stuff.
Tidak, semua normal. Aku lihat hal-hal terkait agen intelijen.
Don't you find it suspicious that the only survivor of Operation Ciénaga
Kau tak curiga satu-satunya penyintas dari Operasi Ciénaga
is its top commander?
adalah komandan utamanya?
And even more suspicious, the assassin didn't try to kill him, but to kidnap him.
Lebih mencurigakan, pembunuh itu tak membunuhnya, tapi menculiknya.
Has my kidnapper been identified?
Penculikku sudah dikenali?
No, he's not on file.
Tidak, dia tak ada di berkas.
Nor any of those responsible for the embassy bombings.
Serta yang bertanggung jawab atas pengeboman kedutaan.
Of course he hasn't been identified.
Tentu dia belum dikenali.
It takes a lot of money, resources, a Diana the Huntress like you
Butuh banyak uang, sumber daya, Diana sang Pemburu sepertimu
to reach that level of professionalism and invisibility.
untuk mencapai tingkat profesionalisme dan tak terlihat.
And you already know all of this because you know exactly who hired them.
Kau sudah tahu semua ini karena kau tahu siapa yang menyewa mereka.
And we'll tell you. In due time.
Kami akan memberitahumu nanti.
Right, so, I would like to ask you this.
Benar, aku ingin menanyakan ini.
Did you have contact with the deceased in recent months?
Apa kau menghubungi almarhum beberapa bulan terakhir?
We know you did, Mr. Ancares.
Kami tahu, Tn. Ancares.
You just need to confirm.
Kau cuma perlu memastikan.
That's correct.
Itu benar.
A journalist contacted Celia about a month ago.
Seorang jurnalis menghubungi Celia sebulan lalu.
She knew a lot of details about Ciénaga
Dia tahu banyak detail tentang Ciénaga
and wanted to talk to all of us to publish a report.
dan ingin bicara dengan kami semua untuk menerbitkan laporan.
It shouldn't have been that day.
Seharusnya bukan hari itu.
There were too many civilians. It got out of hand.
Terlalu banyak warga sipil. Tak terkendali.
- Did you have contact with her? - No, I didn't.
- Apa kau menghubunginya? - Tidak.
But the five of us met up because we didn't know how to proceed.
Kami berlima bertemu karena tak tahu cara melanjutkan.
LONDON (UNITED KINGDOM)
LONDON (BRITANIA RAYA)
Celia informed us that the journalist knew everything about the operation
Celia bilang jurnalis itu tahu tentang operasinya
and that she didn't reveal who her source was,
dan dia tak mengungkapkan sumbernya,
but she knew things that only those of us involved could know.
tapi dia tahu yang hanya diketahui kami yang terlibat.
So, obviously, that meeting was very tense.
Jadi, jelas, pertemuan itu sangat menegangkan.
Could you be more precise?
Bisa lebih jelas?
You know they're playing games.
Kau tahu mereka main-main.
They're going to shoot at any moment.
Mereka akan menembak kapan saja.
Let's see...
Mari kita lihat...
Do you have the name of the journalist?
Kau tahu nama jurnalisnya?
Does your intelligence center know you're dumb?
Apa pusat intelijenmu tahu kau bodoh?
Mr. Ancares, be very careful with me. We're not in Spain, okay?
Tn. Ancares, hati-hati. Kita bukan di Spanyol.
I'll ask you the question again.
Aku akan bertanya lagi.
Do you have the name of the journalist? Yes or no? It's very simple, even for you.
Kau tahu nama jurnalisnya? Ya atau tidak? Sederhana, bahkan untukmu.
There was no journalist.
Tidak ada jurnalis.
The journalist was bait to mark us and, subsequently, eliminate us.
Jurnalis itu umpan untuk menandai dan menyingkirkan kami.
Who? Who wanted to eliminate you?
Siapa yang mau menyingkirkan kalian?
This is a bore, Diana. We're not making any progress.
Ini membosankan, Diana. Kita tak membuat kemajuan.
Would you be so kind as to tell us who it is?
Bisakah kau beri tahu kami siapa orangnya?
What is it?
Ada apa?
Fucking interference.
Gangguan sialan.
- Did you hear that? - Yes.
- Kau dengar itu? - Ya.
We're not the only ones listening in.
Bukan hanya kita mendengarkan.
The signal's coming from the hotel. Above us.
Sinyalnya dari kamar di atas kita.
Boss, keep doing what you're doing and look out the window.
Bos, terus lakukan itu dan lihat ke luar jendela.
We're being spied on.
Kita dimata-matai.
Why did you disappear after the incident in Tallinn?
Mengapa kau menghilang setelah insiden di Tallinn?
Because I was so scared
Karena aku sangat takut
that I was literally crapping liquid in my pants.
hingga aku buang air besar di celanaku.
Right, but you could've asked the CNI for help.
Benar, tapi kau bisa minta bantuan CNI.
Sure, I could.
Tentu saja, aku bisa.
I could've done that.
Aku bisa melakukannya.
- But I didn't. - Why not?
- Namun, tak kulakukan. - Mengapa?
Let's cut the bullshit, Diana the Huntress.
Hentikan, Diana sang Pemburu.
It was clear someone had betrayed us.
Ada yang mengkhianati kami.
That someone could only be from the CNI,
Mungkin seseorang dari CNI
or from another agency with access to very sensitive intel.
atau agensi lain yang punya akses ke intel sensitif.
Twenty dead in a foreign country, that's sensitive enough.
Dua puluh orang tewas di negara asing, itu cukup sensitif.
From here on out, nothing that happens will be accidental.
Mulai sekarang, tak ada yang terjadi secara kebetulan.
Because coincidences, Diana, don't exist in our line of work.
Karena kebetulan, Diana, tak ada dalam pekerjaan kita.
I don't understand. What do you mean?
Aku tak mengerti. Apa maksudmu?
I'm saying the shit we're floating in right now is 12 floors deep.
Maksudku, kita mengalami masalah setinggi 12 lantai.
This floor, you and I...
Lantai ini, kau dan aku
are up to here in it.
terkubur sampai sini.
If we keep playing spy games,
Jika terus bermain mata-mata,
that shit's going to rise at least eight floors higher.
itu akan naik setidaknya delapan lantai.
So you decide.
Jadi, kau yang putuskan.
- Twentieth floor. - Confirmed.
- Lantai 20. - Dikonfirmasi.
Twentieth floor, room 20-06.
Lantai 20, kamar 20-06.
- Vivi, go. - What are we playing at,
- Vivi. - Apa yang dilakukan,
with all the shit that you and I have, Diana...
dengan semua masalah kita, Diana...
Let's recap.
Mari kita rekap.
Alonso.
Alonso.
In 1987, there was carnage on the most important day
Pada tahun 1987, terjadi pembantaian di hari terpenting
of the Flower Festival in Medellín.
Festival Bunga di Medellín.
The massacre was attributed to a war between cartels.
Pembantaian itu dikaitkan dengan perang antar kartel.
Until we discovered that a group of Spanish spies acted without our consent
Sampai kami tahu sekelompok mata-mata Spanyol bertindak tanpa izin kami
and were responsible for the operation.
dan bertanggung jawab atas operasi itu.
And now someone is eliminating them.
Kini seseorang menghabisi mereka.
Esteban Furiase, Teo Furiase's firstborn and heir to his empire.
Esteban Furiase, anak sulung Teo Furiase dan pewaris kerajaannya.
Okay, clear.
Baik, aman.
All clear. You can come up.
Aman. Silakan naik.
Good.
Bagus.
Thirty-seven years ago,
Tiga puluh tujuh tahun lalu,
Esteban Furiase lost his father in your sloppy operation.
Esteban Furiase kehilangan ayahnya dalam operasimu yang ceroboh.
He's looking for you and he's going after each one of you.
Dia mencarimu dan mengejar kalian.
We found out and we want to know what happened
Kami mengetahuinya dan ingin tahu yang terjadi
before another shit show like that blows up in our faces.
sebelum masalah lain seperti itu muncul.
- Any developments? - Marlon, it's all bugged.
- Ada perkembangan? - Marlon, semua disadap.
Boss, you have a mole in there with you.
Bos, ada mata-mata bersamamu di sana.
The bug is broadcasting live.
Penyadap itu disiarkan langsung.
Track the IP.
Lacak IP-nya.
- It's showing as Medellín. - Medellín?
- Itu di Medellín. - Medellín?
A ranch.
Sebuah peternakan.
It's La Ciénaga.
Itu La Ciénaga.
Boss, it's Esteban Furiase.
Bos, itu Esteban Furiase.
I need you to understand the situation right now.
Aku ingin kau memahami situasinya.
One of the people in that room with you
Salah seorang di ruangan itu denganmu
is a goddamn mole from Esteban Furiase's cartel.
adalah mata-mata dari kartel Esteban Furiase.
Cough if you want us to cut the feed, but that person will notice.
Batuk jika mau kami putus saluran, tapi dia akan tahu.
It seems like the case has been solved.
Tampaknya kasus ini sudah terpecahkan.
We already have our killer, don't we?
Kita sudah dapat pembunuhnya, bukan?
As you say, Elena, it seems.
Seperti katamu, Elena, tampaknya begitu.
The idea that Esteban Furiase is avenging
Ide bahwa Esteban Furiase membalas
the death of his father is a solid hypothesis,
kematian ayahnya itu hipotesis kuat,
but it's still just a hypothesis.
tapi itu sekadar hipotesis.
You have the evidence that Esteban Furiase is behind the murders.
Kalian punya bukti Esteban Furiase adalah dalang pembunuhan itu.
Arrest him and we'll handle the extradition.
Tangkap dia, kami tangani ekstradisinya.
- No, it's not that simple. - Why?
- Tidak, tak semudah itu. - Mengapa?
We'll hand over Esteban Furiase,
Kami serahkan Esteban Furiase
but only when we have the full story. We're missing the key piece.
setelah tahu cerita lengkapnya. Kami kehilangan bagian pentingnya.
So let's go back to the beginning.
Jadi, mari kembali ke awal.
Why kill four agents and keep you alive?
Mengapa bunuh empat agen dan membiarkanmu hidup?
I understand.
Aku mengerti.
What do you understand, Ancares?
Kau mengerti apa, Ancares?
I understand the issue.
Aku mengerti masalahnya.
Let's pull the plug. We're going to burst their fucking eardrums.
Mari putus saluran. Kita pecahkan gendang telinga mereka.
Take that, motherfucker.
Rasakan, Keparat.
All right, boss.
Baiklah, Bos.
Time to dance salsa, sweetheart. So I hope you're in shape, you old sissy.
Waktunya beraksi, Sayang. Jadi, semoga kau bugar, Waria Tua.
I need La Ciénaga's security protocols, now. Now!
Aku butuh protokol keamanan La Ciénaga sekarang!
Got it.
Baiklah.
Should we stop?
Kita berhenti?
No, it's okay.
Tidak, tak apa.
So, Esteban Furiase.
Jadi, Esteban Furiase.
One of two things, either you don't have enough evidence
Satu dari dua hal, entah kau tak punya cukup bukti
to go after him or you can't go after him because he has very powerful friends.
atau tak bisa mengejarnya karena dia punya teman yang berkuasa.
We've all been in a situation like that at one time or another, Diana.
Kita semua pernah mengalami situasi seperti itu, Diana.
- Does he still live in La Ciénaga? - Yes, he still lives there.
- Dia masih tinggal di La Ciénaga? - Ya, masih di sana.
He practically never leaves. Why?
Dia tak pernah pergi. Mengapa?
Years ago, La Ciénaga was like a fortress.
Dahulu, La Ciénaga seperti benteng.
You couldn't get in or out.
Kau tak bisa masuk atau keluar.
I imagine it's still like that, correct?
Kurasa masih seperti itu, bukan?
I see you know exactly how things work, don't you?
Kau tahu situasinya, bukan?
Look, stepping into Mr. Furiase's house would be an act of war.
Masuk ke rumah Tn. Furiase akan dianggap tindakan perang.
Especially if we have no evidence.
Terutama jika tak punya bukti.
Diana, go in.
Diana, masuklah.
Do it right.
Lakukan sempurna.
Leave no trace, and we'll all live happily ever after.
Jangan tinggalkan jejak dan kita hidup bahagia selamanya.
You mean, "do it right" like you did in Operation Ciénaga?
Maksudmu seperti pada Operasi Ciénaga?
No, we're not authorizing it for now.
Tidak, kami tak mengizinkannya.
I am sure, my brother,
Aku yakin, Bung,
that there's someone else spying on us.
ada yang memata-matai kita.
So don't let them screw you over first.
Jangan biarkan mereka mendiktemu.
Let's lay our cards on the table.
Mari kita bicara jujur.
Okay, Diana?
Setuju, Diana?
What do you want from me?
Kau mau apa dariku?
I already told you.
Sudah kubilang.
We want the person responsible for the massacre.
Kami ingin penanggung jawab pembantaian itu.
Here goes.
Ini dia.
Get the shield ready, brother.
Siapkan perisainya, Bung.
The person who's truly responsible.
Orang yang bertanggung jawab.
We want Casiel.
Kami mau Casiel.
Casiel?
Casiel?
You never told your people?
Kau tak beri tahu mereka?
- Do you people know who Casiel is? - No.
- Kalian tahu siapa Casiel? - Tidak.
Ancares,
Ancares,
can you clarify who Casiel is
bisa jelaskan siapa Casiel
and why he is not in our files?
dan mengapa tak ada di berkas kita?
Those motherfuckers know.
Para keparat itu tahu.
Who is Casiel?
Siapa Casiel?
- I can't say that. - Are you deaf or what?
- Aku tak bisa katakan. - Apa kau tuli?
I'm asking you a question.
Aku tanya kepadamu.
That's for the old Spaniard to tell you.
Pria tua itu akan memberitahumu.
Only the five of us from La Ciénaga had information about that name.
Hanya kami berlima dari La Ciénaga yang punya informasi tentang nama itu.
And Casiel.
Serta Casiel.
Either tell me how you got to Casiel, or this ends here.
Beri tahu aku bagaimana kau tahu Casiel atau ini berakhir di sini.
No, the intel isn't coming from the dead, it's coming from the Furiase clan.
Tidak, intelnya bukan dari orang mati, tapi berasal dari klan Furiase.
So either you're missing something, or you're yanking our chain, partner.
Jadi, entah kau melewatkan sesuatu atau mempermainkan kami, Kawan.
In an operation three weeks ago, we discovered that Furiase
Dalam operasi tiga minggu lalu, kami mendapati Furiase
had been keeping some information secret for more than 30 years.
telah merahasiakan informasi selama lebih dari 30 tahun.
We had an insider who brought us valuable information.
Ada orang dalam yang memberikan informasi berharga.
All right, Andresito.
Baiklah, Andresito.
See this little camera?
Lihat kamera kecil ini?
You're going to tell it everything you told us.
Kau akan ceritakan semua yang kau katakan.
That's it.
Itu saja.
Go on. Relax, nothing's going to happen to you.
Ayolah. Tenang, tak akan terjadi apa-apa kepadamu.
The money and the ticket are ready. Nothing's going to happen, man. Go on.
Uang dan tiketnya sudah siap. Tak ada yang akan terjadi. Ayolah.
The boss was totally obsessed with that Spanish guy, Ancares.
Bos sangat terobsesi dengan orang Spanyol itu, Ancares.
And he ordered all his embassy colleagues to be taken out.
Dia memerintahkan semua rekan kedutaannya dihabisi.
I want us to go all out with this party.
Aku ingin kita menyukseskan pesta ini.
- I'll take care of it. Leave it to me. - Of course. No, buddy, don't worry.
- Akan kutangani. Serahkan kepadaku. - Tentu saja. Tidak, jangan cemas.
- Andresito. Ciao, my love. - Boss, take care.
- Andresito. Sampai jumpa, Sayang. - Bos, hati-hati.
I went into the house when the boss left and I cloned his computers then.
Aku masuk ke rumah saat Bos pergi dan mengkloning komputernya.
You hear me?
Kau dengar aku?
I opened the drawers and found a smaller computer inside.
Aku membuka laci dan menemukan komputer lebih kecil di dalam.
I cloned it.
Aku mengkloningnya.
And then I noticed that there was also an envelope.
Lalu kulihat ada sebuah amplop juga.
I opened it and inside was a card with a handwritten name on it.
Aku membukanya dan di dalamnya ada kartu dengan nama ditulis tangan.
And what was that name?
Siapa nama itu?
Casiel.
Casiel.
There you go. That's it.
Itu dia. Cukup.
We're looking at Furiase's computer, where we found that hidden folder.
Kami lihat komputer Furiase dan menemukan folder tersembunyi itu.
Who is Casiel, Mr. Ancares?
Siapa Casiel, Tn. Ancares?
So, you have his guy's testimony and the computer evidence. Go get Furiase.
Kau punya kesaksian anak buahnya dan bukti komputer. Tangkap Furiase.
We've already established that entering Furiase's house
Kita sepakat bahwa memasuki rumah Furiase
would be a declaration of war.
akan jadi pernyataan perang.
Besides, Andresito showed up dead two days after those images.
Lagi pula, Andresito ditemukan tewas dua hari usai foto itu.
Wow, what a coincidence.
Kebetulan sekali.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I'll give you Casiel when you guarantee my safety and my family's.
Akan kuberikan Casiel saat kau jamin keselamatanku dan keluargaku.
And you'll only be able to guarantee that once Esteban Furiase goes down, okay?
Kau hanya bisa menjamin itu setelah Esteban Furiase mati, paham?
Your call. Take it or leave it.
Terserah kau. Terima atau tinggalkan.
Where are you going?
Kau mau ke mana?
I'm going for a smoke.
Aku mau merokok.
You guys have a lot to talk about.
Banyak yang harus kalian bicarakan.
One last thing, you have an Esteban Furiase soldier in this room.
Satu hal lagi, ada prajurit Esteban Furiase di ruangan ini.
- He's bugged the microphones, the cameras... - Go get him!
- Dia menyadap mikrofon, kamera... - Tangkap dia!
Oh, my word...
Astaga...
Easy, Diana, easy.
Tenanglah, Diana.
Everything's fine for now. We've managed to disconnect their signal.
Semua terkendali. Kami berhasil memutus sinyalnya.
Remember that my offer is nonnegotiable.
Ingat, tawaranku tak bisa ditawar.
You give me Esteban, I give you Casiel.
Kau berikan Esteban dan aku berikan Casiel.
I want that in writing, Elena.
Aku mau itu tertulis, Elena.
- I don't agree with this. - No.
- Aku tak setuju. - Tidak.
When this is over, I want all three of you in my office.
Setelah ini, aku ingin kalian bertiga menemuiku.
- Diana. - I told you not now.
- Diana. - Jangan sekarang.
Keep your hands open.
Buka tanganmu.
Keep monitoring, keep monitoring.
Terus pantau.
You're a real son of a bitch, but you're a genius, Marlon.
Kau memang bajingan, tapi kau genius, Marlon.
You're a sly dog, boss.
Kau anjing yang licik, Bos.
Ancares, who is Casiel?
Ancares, siapa Casiel?
Relax, Zeta, relax.
Tenang, Zeta.
We just exposed one of his soldiers inside the heart of the DNI,
Kita baru saja mengekspos salah satu prajuritnya di DNI,
so it's very likely they've infiltrated the part of the CNI that exposed us.
jadi kemungkinan mereka menyusupi bagian CNI yang mengekspos kita.
As for Casiel, one thing at a time.
Aku jelaskan Casiel nanti.
Right now, it's not safe to share anything.
Saat ini, tak aman berbagi apa pun.
Did he break down and tell you who he was working for?
Apa dia mengaku dan beri tahu bekerja untuk siapa?
Only that an intermediary offered him money
Perantara menawarinya uang
to tap the building's cameras and microphones, nothing more.
untuk menyadap kamera dan mikrofon gedung, itu saja.
A journalist, an intermediary... Esteban Furiase is doing his homework.
Jurnalis, perantara... Esteban Furiase sudah merencanakannya.
But there's good news. The DNI agrees to your demands,
Namun, ada kabar baik. DNI setuju permintaanmu,
in exchange for you handing over Casiel.
jika kau menyerahkan Casiel.
Ancares, who is Casiel? Why didn't the CNI have any record of him?
Ancares, siapa Casiel? Mengapa CNI tak punya catatan tentang dia?
What the fuck do the Colombians want to do with Casiel?
Apa yang orang Kolombia inginkan dari Casiel?
I have no fucking idea, nor do I care.
Aku tak tahu dan tak peduli.
Was he an agent of ours?
Apa dia agen kita?
Did he gave the order to act
Dia beri perintah bertindak
and that's why he was taken out of circulation?
dan itu alasan dia disingkirkan?
Ancares, who is he? Why are you protecting him?
Ancares, siapa dia? Mengapa kau melindunginya?
What's wrong? I can't hear anything.
Ada apa? Aku tak bisa dengar.
What happened?
Ada apa?
We lost him.
Kita kehilangan dia.
Why do you think Casiel is a man?
Mengapa kau berpikir Casiel seorang pria?
Is Casiel a woman?
Apa Casiel wanita?
With all her light and darkness,
Meski ada kekurangan,
she's been the most loyal agent the House has ever known.
dia agen paling setia yang pernah ada.
We asked her for Tirapu, and she gave us Tirapu,
Kami meminta Tirapu dan dia memberikannya,
sacrificing the unimaginable.
mengorbankan hal tak terbayangkan.
Her name.
Namanya.
Is she still alive?
Dia masih hidup?
I could give you her name, but you'll never get Casiel.
Aku bisa beri namanya, tapi kau tak akan temukan Casiel.
Why?
Mengapa?
Because the Casiel you and I knew doesn't exist anymore.
Casiel yang kita kenal sudah tak ada.
She doesn't operate like we do now.
Dia tak beroperasi seperti kita.
But her loyalty's still alive, isn't it?
Namun, kesetiaannya masih hidup, bukan?
Don't give me that fucking look. That's why you chose her son,
Jangan menatapku begitu. Itu sebabnya kau memilih putranya,
because you knew he'd see it through.
karena kau tahu dia akan lakukan.
Ancares, don't play with fire.
Ancares, jangan bermain api.
You and I will play with fire in this life and in the next.
Kita bermain api di kehidupan ini dan berikutnya.
Casiel is Pilar.
Casiel adalah Pilar.
And that's the end of the fucking conversation.
Percakapan ini selesai.
Come back here.
Kembali ke sini.
Check if there's some kind of signal jammer.
Periksa apa ada pengacak sinyal.
- Will this take long? - I don't know.
- Ini akan lama? - Entahlah.
You're the one who knows around here...
Kau yang tahu di sini...
But I don't know.
Aku tak tahu.
What role did Pilar play in Ciénaga?
Apa peran Pilar di Ciénaga?
I can't tell you that yet.
Aku belum bisa beri tahu.
How long have you known that Iago is your son?
Sejak kapan kau tahu Iago putramu?
It's my family, Elena. I was always a little ahead of you all.
Ini keluargaku, Elena. Aku selalu lebih unggul dari kalian.
Are you going to tell him?
Kau akan beri tahu dia?
In good time. For now, let everyone keep thinking
Nanti. Saat ini, biarkan semua berpikir
that Casiel is a man, okay?
bahwa Casiel adalah pria, ya?
And why are you telling me?
Mengapa memberitahuku?
If I don't survive, you have to do what it takes
Jika aku mati, kau harus lakukan apa pun
to get these motherfuckers to take Furiase out of the equation.
agar para bajingan ini menyingkirkan Furiase.
You know perfectly well that Colombia will not officially act against Furiase.
Kau tahu Kolombia tak akan bertindak secara resmi melawan Furiase.
He's too powerful.
Dia terlalu berkuasa.
But they're offering support for your team.
Namun, mereka menawarkan dukungan.
Are you schizophrenic, Elena? Can you see any team right now?
Kau skizofrenia, Elena? Kau melihat ada tim?
You are our best asset here. You have contacts.
Kau aset terbaik kami. Kau punya kenalan.
Elena, I'm retired.
Elena, aku pensiun.
- Retired people go fishing. - Ancares, I want Furiase,
- Pensiunan memancing. - Ancares, aku mau Furiase
and the price is Casiel's identity.
dan harganya adalah identitas Casiel.
So we get Furiase, you rat out Casiel,
Jadi, kita dapat Furiase, kau beri tahu Casiel,
I get protection for you and your family,
aku berikan perlindungan untukmu dan keluargamu,
and you go fishing. For as long as you want.
dan kau pergi memancing. Selama yang kau mau.
Someday you won't float in the shit anymore and I'll be there to see it.
Suatu hari kau akan jatuh dan aku akan melihatnya.
Are you guys there?
Kalian dengar?
Hey! Hey. What happened?
Hei! Apa yang terjadi?
Find out why the fuck you can't hear me.
Cari tahu kenapa kalian tak bisa dengar.
Ancares, the signal went. What did we miss?
Sinyal hilang. Apa yang terlewat?
You're not going to like it, Marlo. Not one fucking bit.
Kau tak akan menyukainya sama sekali, Marlo.
I'm on my way.
Aku dalam perjalanan.
Very well.
Baiklah.
Pack everything up, we're going to Medellín.
Kemasi semuanya, kita akan pergi ke Medellín.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
What did the official tell you?
Apa kata aparat itu?
That $250,000 buys 15 minutes of darkness.
Uang 250.000 dolar itu memberikan waktu 15 menit.
We'd agreed on 30 minutes.
Kita sudah sepakat 30 menit.
Welcome to Medellín, Colombia.
Selamat datang di Medellín.
Well, for 15 minutes, we'll be ghosts in that maze.
Selama 15 menit, kita tak akan terdeteksi di sistem.
Then we're left with our pants down.
Lalu kita akan terekspos.
If we want to quit, this is the time to do it. It's up to you.
Jika kita ingin berhenti, ini saatnya. Itu keputusanmu.
Marlon, over to you.
Marlon, giliranmu.
Very well. Welcome to La Ciénaga,
Baiklah. Selamat datang di La Ciénaga,
Daddy Teo's estate.
kediaman Ayah Teo.
Upgraded with the best technology,
Dilengkapi dengan teknologi terbaik,
security cameras with motion sensors,
kamera keamanan dengan sensor gerakan,
and biometric sensors inside the house.
dan sensor biometrik di dalam rumah.
Your contact will disable the security, won't he?
Kontakmu akan mematikan keamanannya, bukan?
No, madam. The 250 only covered disabling passive security.
Tidak, Bu. Uang 250 hanya mencakup mematikan sistem keamanan pasif.
I'll handle the generators.
Aku tangani generatornya.
What I have no clue about is who's going to deal
Aku tak tahu siapa yang akan mengatasi
with that pack of motherfuckers.
para penjaga itu.
How many men?
Berapa banyak?
Twelve on the ranch and a few trusted ones inside the house.
Dua belas di peternakan dan beberapa di dalam rumah.
Main bedroom?
Kamar tidur utama?
From the size, we think this is the master bedroom,
Dari ukurannya, kami duga ini kamar tidur utama,
so Esteban and Miss Venezuela 2015 are sleeping here.
Esteban dan Nona Venezuela 2015 tidur di sini.
And in this one, the children.
Di sini, anak-anak.
- How many children in total? - Two, the pair.
- Ada berapa? - Dua, laki-laki dan perempuan.
That asshole lives with his mother-in-law.
Bajingan itu tinggal bersama ibu mertuanya.
- You have to be a real sissy-- - I want that bastard alive.
- Hanya pengecut... - Aku mau bajingan itu hidup-hidup.
Documents, wire transfers, payments to hit men.
Dokumen, transfer, pembayaran pembunuh bayaran.
To extradite him, we have to link him to the embassy murders,
Untuk ekstradisi, kita harus kaitkan ke pembunuhan kedutaan
and I'm not settling for four shitty laptop photos. Got it?
dan aku tak mau menerima empat foto laptop payah. Paham?
Fifteen minutes. Quick and clean. When you have the package,
Lima belas menit. Cepat. Saat kau dapat paketnya,
Marlon will pick you up at the meeting point.
Marlon jemput di titik pertemuan.
That's right.
Itu benar.
Zeta. Alive.
Zeta. Hidup-hidup.
Very good. Flaco. Vivi.
Baik. Flaco. Vivi.
We should be one hour from blackout.
Pemadamannya satu jam lagi.
One hour.
Satu jam.
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
Guys, what happened to the lights?
Ada apa dengan lampunya?
Send five over there.
Kirim lima orang ke sana.
What's going on?
Ada apa?
Boss, all of La Ciénaga is without power.
Bos, seluruh La Ciénaga mati lampu.
The generator?
Generatornya?
It's been tampered with, boss.
Sudah dirusak, Bos.
- Let's go get the children. - Baby, what's happening?
- Ayo jemput anak-anak. - Sayang, ada apa?
Princess, wake up.
Putri, bangun.
- Wake up, little princess. - Sweetie, my prince.
- Bangun, Putri Kecil. - Sayang, Pangeranku.
- It's going to be all right. - Wake up, my love.
- Tak apa-apa. - Bangun, Sayang.
- It will be all right. - Is something wrong?
- Ada masalah?
- It'll be all right. - Nothing, the power went out.
- Tak apa-apa. - Tenang, listrik mati.
Take the children to the living room.
Bawa anak-anak ke ruang tamu.
Come on, sweetie. Let's go. That's it.
Ayo, Sayang. Ayo pergi. Itu dia.
Everything in order?
Sudah ditangani?
Yes, sir.
Ya, Pak.
We have all the men combing the estate.
Semua orang menyisir perkebunan.
But if you need to grab something, you better do it now.
Jika kau butuh sesuatu, lakukan sekarang.
From the office.
Dari kantor.
Call for backup. Bring in the paramilitaries.
Panggil bantuan. Datangkan paramiliter.
Careful, to the right.
Hati-hati, ke kanan.
Let's go!
Ayo pergi!
Let's go.
Ayo maju.
You're ten minutes in.
Sudah sepuluh menit.
What's going on?
Ada apa?
- No signal. - Relax, relax, relax.
- Tak ada sinyal. - Tenanglah.
You guys hide behind the couch.
Kalian sembunyi di balik sofa.
Anita, come here. Take it.
Anita, kemari. Ambillah.
I'm sorry, they're coming for me.
Maaf, mereka mengincarku.
- Esteban, what's going on? - Protect the children.
- Esteban, ada apa? - Lindungi anak-anak.
- My love, what about you? - Protect the children!
- Bagaimana denganmu? - Lindungi anak-anak!
I'll be right back. Don't move from here.
Aku akan kembali. Tetap di sini.
- Take good care of them. - Yes, sir.
- Jaga mereka. - Baik, Pak.
Right away! We have to protect the boss!
Cepat! Kita harus melindungi Bos!
Fire!
Tembak!
Are you okay?
Kau tak apa-apa?
Two minutes. We have to go.
Dua menit. Kita harus pergi.
Get them out of there, now.
Keluarkan mereka.
Drop your weapon, Furiase.
Jatuhkan senjatamu.
Drop it! Open the curtain. Open the curtain.
Jatuhkan! Buka tirainya.
You were the one who deceived me.
Kau yang mengkhianatiku.
What the fuck are you doing?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Self-defense. Let's go.
Membela diri. Ayo pergi.
Marlon reports that the power is back on.
Marlon melaporkan listrik menyala.
There are several paramilitary cars heading for La Ciénaga.
Ada beberapa mobil paramiliter menuju La Ciénaga.
Zeta, do you have Esteban Furiase?
Zeta, kau menangkap Furiase?
- I don't think they're receiving us. - Zeta!
- Kurasa mereka tak mendengar kita. - Zeta!
- Paramilitaries one minute away. - Ancares, get them out of there.
- Paramiliter berjarak satu menit. - Ancares, keluarkan mereka.
Boss, the paramilitaries are here.
Bos, paramiliter sudah tiba.
I'll have a hard time getting your mob out.
Aku kesulitan mengeluarkan anggotamu.
- Come on. - Get them out.
- Ayo. - Keluarkan mereka.
- Marlon, meeting point. - She's injured.
- Ke titik pertemuan. - Dia terluka.
Extraction, God damn it! Move!
Evakuasi, Berengsek! Cepat!
Get in!
Masuk!
- Come on! - Quick. Let's go.
- Ayo! - Cepat. Ayo.
Get in.
Masuk.
Go, drive! Drive!
Ayo, jalan!
It'll pass in a minute.
Ini akan berlalu sebentar lagi.
I know.
Aku tahu.
- Go, go, go! - Furiase's cell phone.
- Ayo cepat! - Ponsel Furiase.
Thank God there were only 12 men.
Syukur hanya ada 12 orang.
Twelve, twenty-four, thirty-six...
Dua belas, 24, 36...
- It's all the same. - Don't bust my balls!
- Sama saja. - Jangan buat kesal!
Fine.
Baiklah.
Grandpa, returning to base. The pair are safe and sound.
Kakek, kembali ke markas. Pasangan aman.
Okay, good.
Baik, bagus.
- All right. - All right, then.
- Baiklah.
Okay, very good. Very good job. Very good work.
Baiklah, bagus sekali. Kerja bagus.
Right, Zeta. Furiase?
Bagus, Zeta. Furiase?
- Dead. - What?
- Mati. - Apa?
Alpha took him out.
Alfa membunuhnya.
- Shit. Fuck. But why? - Self-defense.
- Sial. Namun, mengapa? - Membela diri.
Furiase's phone.
Ponsel Furiase.
At least we have something.
Setidaknya kita dapat sesuatu.
Thanks, Zeta. Good job. Let's see what we get out of it.
Terima kasih, Zeta. Kerja bagus. Mari periksa.
Very good job.
Bagus sekali.
Good job? Furiase is dead, you know?
Bagus? Furiase mati.
What's with that face?
Mengapa murung?
Would you have preferred to be the dead one?
Apa kau lebih suka jadi yang mati?
Well, no.
Tidak.
One less son of a bitch. We're all glad, Iago.
Kurang satu bajingan. Kita semua senang, Iago.
Boss, she's fine.
Bos, dia baik-baik saja.
A shot to the vest, a hard hit, and a big scare. That's all.
Tembakan ke rompi, hantaman keras, dan ketakutan. Itu saja.
I'm sure you're proud of the shitty job you've done.
Kalian bangga dengan pekerjaan buruk kalian.
You're a real brute.
Kau sungguh kejam.
Roll it back.
Putar kembali.
- This? - Yeah, it got stuck.
- Ini? - Ya, tersangkut.
I'm not so sure.
Entahlah.
- Yes, rewind it. - Okay.
- Ya, putar ulang. - Baik.
How are you doing?
Bagaimana keadaanmu?
- Everything is in order. Thank you. - Okay.
- Semua baik-baik saja. Terima kasih. - Baiklah.
- You have something, right? - No, for the moment, there's nothing.
- Kau dapat sesuatu, bukan? - Untuk saat ini, tak ada apa-apa.
- Any good news on that phone? - No.
- Ada kabar baik dengan ponselnya? - Tidak.
Nothing yet.
Belum ada.
Well then.
Baiklah.
Your turn. Where's Casiel?
Giliranmu. Di mana Casiel?
You just get well. We'll talk about it later.
Kau baru dirawat. Kita bahas nanti.
Alpha, the deal was Furiase. Alive.
Alfa, kesepakatannya adalah Furiase hidup.
Dead or alive. What you needed was evidence against him.
Hidup atau mati. Kau butuh bukti terhadapnya.
You have his cell phone.
Kau punya ponselnya.
I'll tell you what, Alpha.
Begini saja, Alfa.
As soon as we know what's on that cell phone, we'll talk.
Begitu kami tahu isi ponselnya, kita akan bicara.
Casiel. Or none of you are going anywhere.
Casiel. Atau kalian tak akan ke mana-mana.
- Elena. - Coming.
- Elena. - Ya.
Okay, Ancares.
Baik, Ancares.
That's it.
Itu dia.
It's about fucking time you start talking.
Sudah waktunya kau mulai bicara.
Where's Casiel?
Di mana Casiel?
Why are you so protective of her?
Mengapa kau melindunginya?
Right, I'm protecting her.
Ya, aku melindunginya.
I'm protecting her.
Aku melindunginya.
How do you know Casiel is a woman? I've never told anyone who isn't dead.
Bagaimana kau tahu Casiel wanita? Aku tak pernah beri tahu yang belum mati.
Don't underestimate me. It was me who unearthed the case.
Jangan meremehkanku. Aku yang mengungkap kasusnya.
We've been after her for years.
Kami sudah lama mengejarnya.
Casiel was...
Casiel adalah
our most valuable source of intel.
sumber informasi kami yang paling berharga.
Getting into La Ciénaga was impossible,
Masuk ke La Ciénaga mustahil,
so the House did the only thing they're good at.
Agensi melakukan satu-satunya keahlian mereka.
They sent a woman undercover.
Mengirim wanita untuk menyamar.
A woman whose identity and role were kept completely secret.
Wanita yang identitas dan perannya sangat dirahasiakan.
Back then, her name was Sara Varela.
Dahulu, namanya Sara Varela.
She joined the National Police
Dia masuk Kepolisian Nasional
because her father was one of the Civil Guardsmen killed by Tirapu.
karena ayahnya anggota Garda Sipil yang dibunuh Tirapu.
- Long live the Civil Guard! - Long may it live!
- Hidup Garda Sipil! - Selamanya!
Her motivation was very strong.
Motivasinya sangat kuat.
That's why she was going to be so valuable to us,
Itu sebabnya dia berharga bagi kami,
because she would be loyal to the end. And she was.
karena dia setia hingga akhir. Itu terbukti.
Obviously, they sent her to Colombia to win over the Fury of God
Dia dikirim ke Kolombia untuk memikat Amarah Tuhan
- and get to Tirapu through him. - Sara.
- dan mendekati Tirapu. - Sara.
- Inés. Pleased to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
- Inés. Senang jumpa. - Senang bertemu.
- Éric. - How's it going? Nice to meet you.
- Éric. - Apa kabar? Senang bertemu kau.
- Lucas. - Nice to meet you.
- Lucas. - Senang bertemu denganmu.
Furiase had lost his wife, and getting her into his bed
Furiase kehilangan istrinya dan merayunya
seemed a reasonable option to obtain information.
tampak masuk akal untuk dapat informasi.
Well, damn.
Astaga.
Pretty, isn't she?
Dia cantik, 'kan?
Average.
Biasa saja.
Average?
Biasa saja?
Sara, this is La Ciénaga.
Sara, ini La Ciénaga.
These are the three zones we'll use to exchange intel.
Ini tiga zona yang digunakan untuk bertukar informasi.
We'll need to come up with a name.
Kita harus mencari nama.
We instructed her on the case
Kami memberinya petunjuk kasusnya
and it was us who turned her into an undercover agent.
dan kami yang mengubahnya menjadi agen yang menyamar.
Sara Varela ceased to exist and became Ana Vázquez.
Sara Varela tak lagi ada dan menjadi Ana Vázquez.
But we, for safety's sake, baptized her as Casiel, an acronym.
Demi keselamatan, kami membaptisnya sebagai Casiel, akronim.
The initials of our six names.
Inisial enam nama kami.
Only the six of us knew her by that name.
Hanya kami berenam yang mengenalnya dengan nama itu.
Well?
Bagaimana?
- She was a goddess. - Shall we? Here.
- Dia bagai dewi. - Ayo? Kemari.
Furiase would crumble like rubble at her feet.
Furiase akan bertekuk lutut di kakinya.
Good old Teo Furiase drowned his sorrows at the Sausalito,
Teo Furiase meredakan kesedihannya di Sausalito,
a place for rich kids on the outskirts of Medellín.
tempat anak-anak kaya di pinggiran Medellín.
We just had to put Casiel on the hook and wait for him to take the bait.
Kami harus menempatkan Casiel dan menunggu dia terpancing.
And he did.
Dia terpancing.
Pedrito, who's that chick?
Pedrito, siapa gadis itu?
- Ana, Mr. Furiase. - Pleased to meet you.
- Ana, Tn. Furiase. - Senang jumpa denganmu.
Sara became Teo's favorite pastime. She began to see and hear things.
Sara menjadi favorit Teo. Dia mulai melihat dan mendengar hal-hal.
And so noble.
Sangat mulia.
Well, and so well surrounded. This is wonderful too, really.
Dikelilingi dengan sangat baik. Ini juga luar biasa.
Come on. To Furiase, of course.
Ayo. Untuk Furiase. tentu saja.
- This is... - Whoa! Wow.
- Ini... - Wah!
Yes, that's what you need, yes.
Ya, itu yang kau butuhkan.
A gift that...
Hadiah yang...
Every Monday, she would give me her reports.
Setiap Senin, dia memberiku laporan.
We would meet incognito, obviously, and...
Tentu saja kami bertemu diam-diam dan...
- Are you okay? - Yeah, yeah.
- Kau baik-baik saja? - Ya.
One day, the inevitable happened and it got complicated.
Lalu hal tak terelakkan terjadi dan jadi rumit.
Why don't we leave this all behind?
Bagaimana jika kita pergi saja?
Surely they can send in others.
Mereka bisa kirim orang lain.
I'm not leaving until I bust that son of a bitch.
Aku tak akan pergi sebelum tangkap bajingan itu.
And she put her life on the line to find out
Dia mempertaruhkan nyawanya untuk cari tahu
everything about the batch of weapons that Tirapu was going to buy from Furiase.
semua tentang senjata yang Tirapu akan beli dari Furiase.
The day, the time, the place, everything.
Hari, waktu, tempat, semuanya.
A perfect operation if it weren't for one small detail.
Operasi yang sempurna jika bukan karena satu hal kecil.
Tirapu was supposed to be the...
Tirapu seharusnya menjadi
finishing touch to so much sacrifice, but that day everything went wrong.
penutup usai banyak pengorbanan, tapi hari itu semuanya berjalan salah.
I'm taking the girl to the Flower Festival.
Aku mengajaknya ke Festival Bunga.
- Have fun, then. - Yes.
- Selamat bersenang-senang. - Ya.
I think we'll be back by 5:00 p.m.
Kami akan kembali pukul 17.00.
- Sure, I'll be here. - Playing it safe, right? Okay, great.
- Tentu, aku di sini. - Bermain aman, ya?
The op went sideways the moment all those civilians got in the way.
Operasinya kacau saat banyak warga sipil menghalangi.
And it could get worse.
Itu bisa lebih buruk.
And it did.
Itu terjadi.
Get me another.
Aku tambah lagi.
Motherfucker.
Berengsek.
To the folks back home,
Untuk mereka di kampung,
as we say here.
seperti kata kita.
You have a call.
Ada telepon.
Please excuse me.
Permisi.
Come on. Dad!
Ayolah. Ayah!
That woman's bad, she's deceiving you.
Wanita itu menipumu.
She's a bitch.
Dia mata-mata.
And I swear that, for a moment,
Aku bersumpah, sejenak,
Sara and I were about to wrap it up like any another mission, but...
Sara dan aku akan mengakhirinya seperti misi lainnya, tapi...
Who the fuck are you?
Siapa kau?
Mommy!
Ibu!
We were just kids.
Kami masih muda.
None of us were prepared for that, none of us.
Tak satu pun dari kami siap untuk hal itu.
- Mommy! - None of us.
- Ibu! - Tak satu pun.
Wake up!
Bangun!
All I cared about was getting her out of there.
Aku cuma mau mengeluarkannya dari sana.
We were all guilty, and in a way, we all...
Kami semua bersalah, di satu sisi, kami semua
died that afternoon.
mati sore itu.
What happened after Ciénaga?
Apa yang terjadi usai Ciénaga?
Look.
Lihat.
Like this. Wave like this.
Melambai seperti ini.
They pulled us out of Colombia, kept us under wraps for a good while,
Mereka mengeluarkan kami dari Kolombia, bersembunyi sementara waktu.
and when we got back to Spain,
Saat kembali ke Spanyol,
Sara and I focused on what really mattered,
Sara dan aku fokus pada hal penting,
starting a family.
memulai sebuah keluarga.
- Our son was born, and our plan... - What the fuck are you saying?
- Putra kami lahir dan rencana kami... - Apa maksudmu?
- ...was to stay involved-- - Fuck you!
- ...tetap terlibat... - Persetan!
- Calm down! - What the fuck are you saying?
- Tenanglah! - Apa maksudmu?
Zeta!
Zeta!
- I should rip your fucking head off, man! - Calm down, damn it!
- Aku akan memenggal kepalamu! - Tenanglah!
- I swear I will, you clown. - This is an order! Stop!
- Aku bersumpah, Badut. - Ini perintah! Hentikan!
- You're a fucking clown! - Shut up, that's enough, damn it.
- Kau badut sial! - Diam, sudah cukup. Astaga.
- Don't fucking touch me. - That's enough!
- Jangan sentuh aku. - Cukup!
You're a fucking clown. You're a clown, man.
Kau badut sialan.
- Okay. That's enough, man, damn it. - Fuck you. Clown!
- Baik. Sudah cukup. - Persetan kau. Badut!
Are you okay? Zeta.
Kau tak apa-apa? Zeta.
Look...
Dengar...
I don't know what's going on between you.
Aku tak tahu ada apa antara kalian.
What I do know is that Casiel was the one who started the shooting at the festival.
Yang kutahu adalah Casiel yang memulai penembakan di festival.
So stop with the bullshit and tell me where she is.
Jadi, hentikan omong kosong ini dan katakan di mana dia.
Our plan was to stay tied to the service, under the radar.
Rencana kami adalah tetap mengabdi, tanpa menarik perhatian.
But when our son turned one,
Saat putra kami berusia satu tahun,
the House told us Colombia and the Furiase clan were investigating
Agensi beri tahu bahwa Kolombia dan klan Furiase menyelidiki
who was behind the massacre.
siapa dalang pembantaian itu.
If they found out, we were dead.
Jika mereka tahu, kami mati.
So CESID pulled us out,
Jadi CESID mengeluarkan kami,
because it was the only way they could protect themselves.
karena itu satu-satunya cara mereka bisa melindungi diri.
You have your destination
Kalian memiliki tujuan
and the necessary information to start a new life.
dan informasi yang diperlukan untuk mulai hidup baru.
So they faked our deaths and buried us all.
Mereka memalsukan kematian dan mengubur kami semua.
Sara became Pilar and I became Salvador Ancares.
Sara menjadi Pilar dan aku menjadi Salvador Ancares.
Sara had crossed lines
Sara melewati batas
the House would never take responsibility for.
yang tak akan pernah diakui oleh Agensi.
That's why they pulled us out of Spain for good, with new identities.
Itu sebabnya kami dikeluarkan dari Spanyol, dengan identitas baru.
And we were both ready to start a new life,
Kami berdua siap memulai hidup baru,
another one, far away from Spain,
kehidupan lain, jauh dari Spanyol,
but at that time, too much had happened between us.
tapi saat itu, terlalu banyak yang terjadi di antara kami.
And only I got on that plane.
Cuma aku yang naik ke pesawat.
Ancares, this Pilar, Casiel,
Ancares, Pilar ini, Casiel,
whatever her name is, where can we find her?
siapa pun namanya, di mana kami bisa menemukannya?
I don't know.
Aku tak tahu.
And have you heard from your son?
Ada kabar dari putramu?
Not a trace.
Tidak ada jejak.
Landa.
Landa.
This all smells rotten to you too, doesn't it?
Kau juga merasa ada yang tak beres, bukan?
I still don't know where the stench is coming from...
Aku masih tak tahu apa yang tak beres...
but I'm going to find out, partner.
tapi akan kucari tahu, Kawan.
What bullshit is that clown talking about?
Apa yang dibicarakan badut itu?
- Zeta, I know it's hard. - What is hard?
- Zeta, aku tahu sulit. - Apa yang sulit?
I know it's hard to digest.
Aku tahu sulit diterima.
Ancares told me about it at the DNI, and we found documents
Ancares memberitahuku di DNI dan kami temukan dokumen
- linking your mother to Operation Ciénaga. - What are you saying?
- terkait ibumu dengan Operasi Ciénaga. - Apa maksudmu?
- That my mother is an agent? - I know it's hard to understand,
- Bahwa ibuku seorang agen? - Aku tahu ini sulit dipahami,
but Ancares isn't lying.
tapi Ancares jujur.
You guys are going to drive me fucking crazy.
Kalian akan membuatku gila.
I don't know who's lying and who's not. I want an explanation.
Aku tak tahu siapa yang bohong. Aku ingin penjelasan.
- And I'll give it to you. - I want you to tell me now.
- Akan kujelaskan nanti. - Beri tahu sekarang.
Look, I don't care. Tell me now.
Aku tak peduli. Beri tahu sekarang.
We'll talk later. We'll talk later.
Kita akan bicara nanti.
Do we know how many people were killed in the operation yet?
Apa kita tahu berapa banyak yang tewas dalam operasi?
They've counted 15 so far, but there will definitely be more.
Sejauh ini 15, tapi pasti akan lebih banyak.
We'll see, because Furiase can't tell us anything anymore.
Lihat nanti, Furiase tak bisa beri tahu apa-apa lagi.
But we have the phone and there's much information there, right?
Kita dapat ponselnya dan banyak informasi di sana, bukan?
Let's see what we find.
Mari lihat ada apa.
- Has anything else shown up? - No. Hello.
- Ada lagi yang lain? - Tidak. Halo.
How are you? Are you okay?
Apa kabar? Kau baik-baik saja?
Yes.
Ya.
- Do we know anything? Do we have him? - Negative.
- Dapat sesuatu? Dia ditemukan? - Tidak.
Casiel is a woman, as I imagined. She changed her identity several times.
Casiel adalah wanita, seperti dugaanku. Dia ubah identitas beberapa kali.
Currently, her name is Pilar,
Saat ini, namanya Pilar
and that is the only useful thing Ancares told us.
dan hanya itu hal berguna yang Ancares katakan.
Right...
Baiklah...
That guy's yanking our chain.
Dia mempermainkan kita.
Okay.
Baiklah.
Let's see what we can get out of him.
Mari lihat yang bisa didapat darinya.
Please accompany the Spaniards to the hotel
Tolong antar mereka ke hotel
while we corroborate the information.
sementara kami periksa informasinya.
What? No, no, no. No way. We're going back to Spain.
Apa? Tidak. Tak bisa. Kami akan kembali ke Spanyol.
Of course, naturally, you can return to Spain whenever you want,
Tentu saja, kalian bisa kembali ke Spanyol kapan pun,
but Ancares stays here until we have Casiel.
tapi Ancares harus serahkan Casiel.
- That's not what we agreed. - We want her whereabouts.
- Bukan itu perjanjiannya. - Kami mau lokasinya.
We do not know. Look,
Kami tak tahu. Dengar,
we can help you look for her, but today, we're leaving,
kami bisa bantu mencari, tapi kami pergi sekarang,
and he's coming with us.
dan dia ikut kami.
- That plane is not leaving. - Landa.
- Pesawat tak akan pergi. - Landa.
Ms. Herrera, if in the next hour, that plane is not leaving for Spain,
Nn. Herrera, jika dalam satu jam pesawat itu tak berangkat ke Spanyol,
I will have to call the minister. Or the president, which will be worse.
aku akan telepon menteri. Atau presiden, yang akan lebih buruk.
Sure.
Tentu.
- You win, Ms. Faron. But... - All right.
- Kalian menang, Nn. Faron. Namun... - Baiklah.
...Alpha goes with you to Spain,
...Alfa ikut ke Spanyol
and we'll continue the investigation there, all right?
dan melanjutkan penyelidikan di sana.
Great, that's a win-win situation.
Bagus, itu saling menguntungkan.
- It was a pleasure meeting you. - Likewise.
- Senang jumpa kau. - Sama-sama.
- We're there if you need anything. - Same here.
- Kami siap jika kau butuh sesuatu. - Kami juga.
This life is very hard, it's...
Kehidupan ini sangat sulit, ini...
But it's what we love. You get used to it.
Namun, kita mencintainya. Kau akan terbiasa.
How long have you known who I am?
Sejak kapan tahu siapa aku?
A father always needs to be two steps ahead of his son.
Ayah harus selalu unggul dua langkah di depan putranya.
And you abandon your family?
Kau meninggalkan keluargamu?
No, it's not that simple.
Tak sesederhana itu.
Your mother wasn't cut out for this life.
Ibumu tak cocok untuk kehidupan ini.
She didn't want to be tied to the service. But I did.
Dia tak mau terikat agensi, tapi aku mau.
I did. So I decided to disappear.
Aku mau. Jadi, aku putuskan untuk menghilang.
At the time, it seemed like a legitimate decision.
Saat itu, keputusannya tampak tepat.
Why did they want you alive?
Kenapa mereka mau kau hidup?
You and I would have done the same.
Kita akan lakukan hal sama.
We would have wanted whoever was closest to Casiel alive.
Kita mau siapa pun yang dekat dengan Casiel hidup.
Are you going to tell me the fucking truth for once?
Apa kau akan katakan yang sebenarnya kali ini?
- The truth. - Yes.
- Yang sebenarnya. - Ya.
Who the fuck knows what the truth is?
Siapa yang tahu kebenarannya?
La Ciénaga swallowed us whole.
La Ciénaga melukai kami semua.
Fucking shitty life!
Kehidupan yang buruk!
It swallowed us whole and never spat us back out.
Itu melukai kami dan tak pernah pulih.
I could never forgive myself for what we did in Colombia.
Aku tak bisa memaafkan diri atas perbuatan di Kolombia.
Seeing your mother every day reminded me of it constantly
Melihat ibumu setiap hari selalu mengingatkanku
and we argued and cried, cried and argued.
dan kami bertengkar, lalu menangis.
One day, I woke up yelling at her,
Suatu hari, aku memakinya,
hating her, shaking her, and told her that...
membencinya, mengguncangnya, dan berkata bahwa...
I was leaving, that I wouldn't come back until I was ready.
aku akan pergi dan tak kembali sampai aku siap.
But that never happened.
Itu tak pernah terjadi.
One day, she called me to tell me that I was nobody to you,
Suatu hari, dia meneleponku untuk bilang aku bukan siapa-siapa bagimu,
that she'd told you that I'd died, that I shouldn't write to you anymore.
bahwa aku sudah mati, dan tak boleh menulis surat lagi.
Because I was sending you postcards.
Karena aku mengirimimu kartu pos.
Of some amazing places I'd been.
Beberapa tempat mengagumkan yang kudatangi.
What did you expect?
Apa yang kau harapkan?
She decided that I didn't deserve to exist for you
Dia memutuskan aku tak pantas ada untukmu
and I decided to respect that.
dan kuputuskan menghormatinya.
Well, you did exist for me.
Kau ada untukku.
Zeta, get your things, we're going home.
Zeta, ambil barangmu, kita akan pulang.
Leave her alone, okay?
Jangan ganggu dia, ya?
No, don't you worry. She's a sick old woman.
Tidak, jangan cemas. Dia wanita tua yang sakit.
- They won't be able to extradite her. - I swear I'll rip your heads off, Elena.
- Mereka tak bisa mengekstradisinya. - Aku akan memenggalmu, Elena.
I'll personally see to it that they do not discover her identity.
Aku akan pastikan mereka tak mengetahui identitasnya.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
For being the worst in your class, you did a good job.
Kerja bagus, mengingat kau yang terburuk di kelas.
Thanks.
Terima kasih.
See you in Madrid.
Jumpa di Madrid.
- It's done. - Bye. It's been a pleasure.
- Selesai. - Sampai jumpa. Senang sekali.
Hey.
Hei.
- Elena is wrong. - How so?
- Elena salah. - Mengapa begitu?
Your mother isn't safe yet. Come.
Ibumu belum aman. Ayo.
What are you saying?
Apa maksudmu?
Come.
Ayo.
Hey, everybody inside!
Hei, semuanya masuk!
Take cover!
Berlindung!
Come!
Ayo!
Get inside!
Masuk!
Okay, hold him there!
Baik, angkat dia di sana!
Look at me, motherfucker!
Lihat aku, Bajingan!
Stay with me, stay with me!
Bertahanlah!
Look at me! Damn it, look at me! Fuck!
Lihat aku! Sial!
Up.
Dudukkan.
Press there, press!
Tekan di sana!
Look at me, motherfucker, look at me!
Lihat aku, Bajingan!
- Press, damn it! - Stay with me, motherfucker. Stay with me!
- Tekan, sial! - Tetap bersamaku, Bajingan!
Why the hell didn't you wait for my signal?
Mengapa kau tak tunggu aba-abaku?
- Did I get him? - Do you have the recording?
- Aku mengenainya? - Kau dapat rekamannya?
Hold on.
Tunggu dahulu.
Pulling the hotel job
Melakukan pekerjaan di hotel
and making them think Esteban Furiase was spying on them is one thing.
dan buat mereka berpikir Furiase memata-matai adalah satu hal.
But a hit inside a fucking military base, surrounded by armed men
Namun, serangan di pangkalan militer, dikelilingi pasukan bersenjata
and no time to prep? That's a whole other story. I want double.
dan tak ada waktu bersiap? Itu cerita lain. Aku mau dobel.
All right. Can I have the recording?
Baiklah. Boleh aku minta rekamannya?
Elena is wrong.
Elena salah.
How so?
Mengapa begitu?
Your mother isn't safe yet. Come.
Ibumu belum aman. Ayo.
You can't hear the last part.
Bagian akhir tak terdengar.
It's the plane, that's not good for shit.
Ada pesawat, itu tak berguna.
- Can't the audio be recovered? - No way.
- Audio tak bisa dipulihkan? - Tak bisa.
I told you to wait for my signal.
Sudah kubilang tunggu aba-abaku.
What do we do now?
Apa yang kita lakukan?
Put a bullet in his leg, run away, what? Do we--
Tembak kakinya, lari, apa? Apa kita...
Target down. How is Ancares?
Target tewas. Bagaimana Ancares?
We're here today to say goodbye to our friend, Salvador.
Kita hadir untuk berpamitan dengan teman kita, Salvador.
Though we feel an immense emptiness and deep sorrow at his passing,
Meski kita merasakan kekosongan dan kesedihan mendalam atas kematiannya,
his memory will live on in our hearts,
kenangannya akan terus hidup dalam hati kita,
and the love we shared will never fade.
dan cinta yang kita miliki tak akan pernah pudar.
We hope that Salvador's family and friends
Kami harap keluarga dan teman Salvador
find comfort in the memories you shared.
menemukan ketenangan dalam kenangan yang ada.
We're here to support you through this.
Kami akan mendukungmu melalui ini.
Pepe, everything okay?
Pepe, semuanya baik?
All is well. Your mother is upstairs with Andreia.
Semua baik. Ibumu di atas dengan Andreia.
"I know what that is, my friend," replied Dixie.
"Aku tahu apa itu, Kawan," jawab Dixie.
"My mother scolded me whenever she noticed that I'd gone to the gym to work out."
"Ibuku memarahiku setiap kali dia tahu aku ke sasana untuk olahraga."
Hey! Iago has just arrived.
Hei! Iago baru saja tiba.
We'll continue another time. I'll leave you with him.
Kita lanjutkan lain waktu. Aku permisi.
- Hello. - Hi.
- Halo. - Hai.
All right, I'm off.
Baiklah, aku pergi.
- Thanks. - You're welcome.
- Terima kasih. - Sama-sama.
I've missed you so much.
Aku merindukanmu.
You're so brave, Mom.
Ibu sangat berani.
Drop your weapon.
Letakkan senjatamu.
I said drop your weapon.
Kubilang letakkan.
On the floor.
Di lantai.
How did you do it?
Bagaimana caramu?
How did you manage to find the Ciénaga Five?
Bagaimana kau menemukan Ciénaga Lima?
Everyone has a price.
Semua ada harganya.
- Celia. - Just a moment.
- Celia. - Tunggu sebentar.
You contacted her, and she led you to the others.
Kau hubungi dia dan dia membawamu ke yang lain.
But they were waiting for you inside too.
Mereka juga menunggumu di dalam.
- Are you sure she was a journalist? - I'm not sure of anything,
- Kau yakin dia jurnalis? - Aku tak yakin,
- otherwise we wouldn't be here. - Let's be specific.
- itu sebabnya di sini. - Lebih spesifik.
Take your time, Celia, what exactly did she tell you?
Pelan-pelan, Celia, apa yang dia katakan kepadamu?
That she had sensitive information about Ciénaga.
Dia punya informasi sensitif soal Ciénaga.
And that she'd write a book.
Dia akan menulis buku.
And who is the source?
Siapa sumbernya?
- She wouldn't say. - Did you tell her anything about her?
- Dia tak mau bilang. - Kau cerita soal dia?
Of course not.
Tentu saja tidak.
But she knew there were six of us
Namun, dia tahu kita berenam
and that the sixth was a woman.
dan yang keenam wanita.
Only someone who was there and saw us could know that.
Hanya orang yang ada di sana dan melihat kita yang tahu itu.
Furiase Jr.
Furiase Jr.
No, Furiase Jr. was not at the festival that afternoon.
Tidak, Furiase Jr. tak ada di festival itu.
Right, but Furiase Jr. knew her.
Benar, tapi Furiase Jr. mengenalnya.
He let the cat out of the bag and warned his father.
Dia membocorkan rahasia dan memperingatkan ayahnya.
Do you think she has something to do with Furiase's son?
Apa dia ada kaitannya dengan putra Furiase?
He's definitely the one who'd want payback the most.
Dia jelas yang paling ingin balas dendam.
They were right.
Mereka benar.
Furiase and I wanted every last one of them.
Furiase dan aku ingin mereka mati.
Did she mention Casiel?
Dia sebutkan Casiel?
Not at all.
Tidak sama sekali.
Give them the name, we tag her,
Beri namanya, kita tandai dia,
and let's see where the hell this all leads. Okay?
dan kita lihat ke mana arahnya. Setuju?
Anyone who said that name would be marked like a counterfeit bill.
Siapa pun yang katakan nama itu akan ditandai seperti uang palsu.
Casiel?
Casiel?
- Can you spell it for me, please? - Sure.
- Bisa tolong dieja? - Tentu.
C-A-S-I...
C-A-S-I...
When you found her and pretended to be a journalist,
Saat bertemu dan pura-pura jadi jurnalis,
Celia set the bait for you.
Celia memasang umpan untukmu.
When the book comes out, I'll let you know.
Aku kabari saat bukunya terbit.
It was only a matter of time.
Hanya soal waktu.
- Goodbye. - Until next time.
- Dah. - Sampai jumpa.
Received. Thank you.
Diterima. Terima kasih.
You used Esteban to carry out the plan and kill the agents.
Kau gunakan Esteban untuk menjalankan rencana dan membunuh para agen.
At the same time, you used Andresito's lies
Lalu, kau gunakan kebohongan Andresito
to get the DNI to go after Furiase and uncover Operation Ciénaga.
agar DNI mengejar Furiase dan mengungkap Operasi Ciénaga.
Open the curtain.
Buka tirainya.
Once you got to Ancares, you had no more use for Furiase.
Begitu dapat Ancares, kau tak perlu Furiase lagi.
You were the one who betrayed--
Kau yang mengkhianati...
I saw you kill him, it wasn't self-defense.
Aku melihatmu membunuhnya, bukan bela diri.
And the same thing happened to Ancares. He caught you.
Hal yang sama terjadi kepada Ancares. Dia memergokimu.
How do you know Casiel is a woman? I've never told anyone who isn't dead.
Bagaimana kau tahu Casiel wanita? Aku tak beri tahu yang belum mati.
Don't underestimate me.
Jangan meremehkanku.
It was me who unearthed the case.
Aku yang mengungkap kasusnya.
We've been after her for years.
Kami sudah lama mengejarnya.
He was about to find out who you were and you hired the hit man.
Dia hampir tahu siapa kau dan kau menyewa pembunuh bayaran.
Hold still.
Jangan bergerak.
Who do you work for?
Kau disuruh siapa?
For myself.
Diriku sendiri.
Why the fuck do you want my mother?
Mengapa menginginkan ibuku?
I said why the fuck do you want my mother?
Kubilang mengapa menginginkan ibuku?
I spent my whole life chasing after her.
Seumur hidup aku mengejarnya.
Your mom caused the festival massacre.
Ibumu menyebabkan pembantaian festival.
Mommy.
Ibu.
Mommy! Help, please!
Ibu! Tolong!
I was there.
Aku ada di sana.
And I saw her.
Aku melihatnya.
Mommy!
Ibu!
Wake up!
Bangun!
While my parents were bleeding to death.
Saat orang tuaku berdarah sampai mati.
My name is Ainara.
Namaku Ainara.
Iago, I have nothing against you.
Iago, kita tak ada masalah.
The DNI is informed.
DNI sudah diberi tahu.
There have been enough deaths, Ainara.
Sudah cukup banyak kematian, Ainara.
Listen to me.
Dengarkan aku.
You're going to put down the gun you have there.
Kau akan meletakkan senjata yang kau punya.
The one hidden on your back.
Yang ada di punggungmu.
You're going to put it on the table.
Kau akan menaruhnya di meja.
It's over.
Sudah berakhir.
You have no way out, you have to trust me.
Kau tak bisa kabur, kau harus memercayaiku.
Look.
Lihat.
That's it now.
Sudah selesai.
Put down your weapon.
Letakkan senjatamu.
Okay.
Baiklah.
Keep your eyes on me.
Tetap lihat aku.
Everything's going to be okay.
Semua akan baik-baik saja.
Keep calm.
Tetap tenang.
That's it.
Bagus.
Leave it there.
Letakkan di sana.
There you go.
Itu dia.
Hello, Casiel.
Halo, Casiel.
- Don't touch me. - Stay still.
- Jangan sentuh. - Diamlah.
Don't move. Stay still.
Jangan bergerak.
Okay, press on it.
Baik, tekan itu.
Right there. Press.
Di sana. Tekan.
That's it.
Bagus.
- Don't touch me! - Stay still. Stay still.
- Jangan sentuh aku! - Jangan bergerak.
Press and turn on your side.
Tekan dan putar ke sisi.
That's it.
Bagus.
Here, please.
Di sini, tolong.
I think that was reckless on your part.
Kurasa kau ceroboh.
You knew everything from the beginning.
Kau tahu semua sejak awal.
- Thank you very much, Zeta. Truly. - Elena.
- Terima kasih, Zeta. Sungguh. - Elena.
I'm coming.
Aku datang.
It's okay.
Tak apa-apa.
Mom.
Ibu.
Hey. Talk to me.
Hei. Bicaralah kepadaku.
Talk to me. Talk to me.
Bicaralah kepadaku.
It's over. It's over.
Sudah berakhir.
They were postcards of...
Ada kartu pos...
Of some amazing places I'd been to.
Beberapa tempat mengagumkan yang kudatangi.
For Iago
Untuk Iago
Dear son,
Anakku sayang,
if you're reading this letter, it means I will no longer be with you.
jika kau baca surat ini, artinya aku sudah tak bersamamu lagi.
It's very difficult for me to write these words,
Sangat sulit bagiku untuk menulis kata-kata ini,
but I have to do it, since I never had the courage to tell you.
tapi aku harus melakukannya, karena aku tak berani memberitahumu.
I'm leaving. See you in a few days, Mom.
Aku pergi. Sampai jumpa beberapa hari lagi, Bu.
Your father was not killed in the line of duty.
Ayahmu tidak tewas saat bertugas.
Don't worry about us. We'll be fine.
Tenang. Kami akan baik-baik saja.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
- Bye.
- Dah. - Sampai jumpa.
When you were very little, I made the decision to separate.
Saat kau masih kecil, aku memutuskan untuk berpisah.
I know you'll have many questions.
Aku tahu kau akan punya banyak pertanyaan.
But I only have one answer.
Namun, aku hanya punya satu jawaban.
I wanted to protect you. Not from him, he loved you deeply, but from myself.
Aku ingin melindungimu. Bukan darinya, dia sangat menyayangimu, tapi dari diriku.
I wanted to bury the woman I once was,
Aku ingin mengubur diriku yang dahulu
and with him, that was impossible.
dan bersamanya, itu tak mungkin.
So I left him and gave him no chance to be your father.
Jadi, kutinggalkan dia dan tak memberinya kesempatan menjadi ayahmu.
I know it's unfair to you,
Aku tahu itu tak adil untukmu,
just as it was to him.
sama seperti untuknya.
The postcards with this letter were sent by him,
Kartu pos dengan surat ini dikirim olehnya,
hoping that one day he'd get to see you
berharap suatu hari dia bisa bertemu denganmu
and recover the love we lost when we were different people.
dan menemukan cinta yang hilang saat kami berbeda.
I hope that one day you can forgive me.
Kuharap suatu hari kau bisa memaafkanku.
I love you.
Aku menyayangimu.
The man who fooled everyone.
Pria yang menipu semua orang.
Who, me? No, brother.
Siapa, aku? Tidak, Kawan.
That was all planned by your dad.
Semua itu direncanakan ayahmu.
Nothing could be done.
Dia tak selamat.
I'm very sorry.
Aku minta maaf.
You have no idea what kind of old man you have.
Kau tak tahu ayah macam apa yang kau miliki.
See what it takes to kill that motherfucker,
Sangat sulit membunuh bajingan itu
and the bullet came this close.
dan pelurunya sedekat ini.
How lucky you are to have him.
Beruntung kau memilikinya.
Where is he?
Di mana dia?
Leaving already?
Kau mau pergi?
I'm going to scratch my balls in Cartagena.
Aku akan bersantai di Cartagena.
Good plan.
Rencana bagus.
Why didn't you kill her?
Mengapa tak membunuhnya?
You know she'll be back for you, don't you?
Kau tahu dia akan kembali untukmu, bukan?
Have a safe trip.
Selamat jalan.
Just like the old son of a bitch.
Persis bajingan tua itu.